Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
I love you.
我爱你。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right.
好的。
Welcome back to the Ethereum Protocol Fellowship Study Group.
欢迎回到以太坊协议研究小组。
This is week eight on the research track,
这是研究轨道上的第八周
and we are here with Barnabé Monod.
我们在这里与BarnabéMonod一起。
from the Robust Incentives Group, part of the Ethereum Foundation research program.
来自以太坊基金会研究计划的一部分的强大的激励小组。
And yeah, he'll be talking today about some NEV and censorship.
是的，他今天将谈论一些NEV和审查制度。
So I'll pass it up to Mario here, give a little bit more in-depth introduction,
因此
and then we'll get started with Barnaby.
然后，我们将开始使用Barnaby。
Thank you so much all for joining our stream today.
非常感谢您今天加入我们的流。
Thank you so much, Barnaby, for being here especially.
非常感谢您，Barnaby，特别是在这里。
it's an honor to have you here because Barnaby is one of the best experts we can have here to cover this topic.
很荣幸能在这里有您，因为Barnaby是我们在这里可以拥有的最好的专家之一来介绍此主题。
Barnaby is from the RoboScientist group, as Josh said, but he's the research scientist,
正如乔什所说，巴纳比来自Roboscientist小组
I believe the leader or the leading position of this group,
我相信该小组的领导者或领导地位，
which is doing a lot of interesting research on the game theory of Ethereum
这对以太坊的游戏理论进行了许多有趣的研究
with the crypto economics that's happening in the staking.
随着加密经济学的出现。
But also previously, a lot of improvements done on Ethereum
但以前，对以太坊进行了许多改进
has been analyzed by Barnaby and Eric, for example, 1559 Models and so on.
例如，Barnaby和Eric分析了1559型模型等。
So Barnaby has a long experience with these topics.
因此，Barnaby在这些主题方面有很长的经验。
topics, and today specifically about MEV and censorship resistance. So, we will have a
主题，今天特别是关于MEV和审查制度的。所以，我们将有一个
deeper look into some recent economic proposals. Yeah, very excited about it. Many people are
更深入地研究一些最近的经济建议。是的，对此非常兴奋。许多人是
excited for this topic, so thanks so much again for being here, Barda. We appreciate
对这个话题感到兴奋，所以再次感谢您在这里，巴达。我们感谢
you joining us. And yeah, the floor is yours. Let's see if we can hear you.
你加入我们。是的，地板是你的。让我们看看我们是否可以听到您的声音。
yeah thank you for having me can you hear me yeah yeah okay um all right perfect uh okay yeah i
是的，谢谢你有我，你能听到我的声音，是的，好吧，好吧，很好，是的，我
i know i was slated to do a talk on mivian censorship and i'll definitely talk about
我知道我原定要对Mivian审查制度进行演讲，我一定会谈论
that too but i want to widen the frame a little bit and talk about this kind of conceptual
那也是，但我想扩大框架并谈论这种概念
framework that i use to to think about the different parts because there's so much
我用来考虑不同部分的框架，因为有很多
happening in Ethereum all the time. So this idea of protocol services, I think it's a good way of
一直在以太坊发生。因此，这是协议服务的想法，我认为这是一种很好的方式
trying to map this out for ourselves. So yeah, I'll give some notes about this and then I'll try
试图为自己映射。是的，我会给我一些笔记，然后我会尝试
to show what might be a good way to think about it and to organize these protocol services.
展示可能是考虑它并组织这些协议服务的好方法。
A very quick intro, though, Mario already said quite a lot. I joined the EF in January 2020.
不过，马里奥已经说了很多简单的介绍。我于2020年1月加入EF。
I've worked on a couple of exciting proposals since then. Our team, the robots incentives group
从那时起，我已经做出了一些令人兴奋的建议。我们的团队，机器人激励小组
now is seven people, including me. So yeah, we have quite the scope and we are excited to always
现在是七个人，包括我。是的，我们有很大的范围，我们很高兴总是
dive into the most, I think, tricky questions that we face. We have a lot of work that's published,
我认为，我们面临的最棘手的问题最深入。我们有很多发表的工作，
we try to do as much in the open as possible, so do check out our website if you can.
我们尝试尽可能多地做，因此，如果可以的话，请访问我们的网站。
What I want to talk about today is three things.
我今天想谈论的是三件事。
So the first thing I'll introduce is very briefly this idea of seeing like a protocol,
因此，我将介绍的第一件事是简短的想法，即像协议一样看到
which is, I would say, my approach to thinking about stuff.
我想说的是我思考事物的方法。
So I'll talk a bit about that.
所以我会谈谈。
And then I want to discuss two services that are pretty much the fundamental services that
然后，我想讨论两项服务，这些服务几乎是基础服务
the protocol is trying to provide, which is first the block production service and then
该协议正在尝试提供，这首先是块生产服务，然后
a consensus service. So let me start here. So the idea of seeing like a protocol is you
共识服务。所以让我从这里开始。所以像协议一样看到的想法是你
have this abstract object, the Ethereum protocol that sort of lives in the sky, that's a network
拥有这个抽象对象，即生存在天空中的以太坊协议，那是一个网络
of all these machines. And when you're a protocol designer, like when you're trying to make
在所有这些机器中。当您是协议设计师时，就像您试图制作
upgrades to Ethereum, you realize that, okay, there are things that the protocol sees, that
升级到以太坊，您意识到，好的，协议看到的某些东西，
protocol acknowledges that it can work with, and there are things it doesn't really see.
协议承认它可以与之使用，并且有些事情并没有真正看到。
And it feels like the art of protocol development is just trying to push the
感觉就像协议开发的艺术只是在试图推动
boundary of what the protocol sees and trying to make it more robust and understand more
协议所看到的边界并试图使其更强大并了解更多
of what's happening in its environment. So this metaphor of, okay, it can see that,
在其环境中发生的事情。因此，这个隐喻可以看到，
it cannot see that, I'll use that throughout the talk.
看不到，我将在整个演讲中使用它。
I wrote a post about this about a year ago, and I was trying to start from the main question
大约一年前，我写了一篇有关此帖子的文章，我正试图从主要问题开始
of where does this protocol credibility come from?
该协议信誉从何而来？
So there's always like calls in the Ethereum community to say, oh, we need to enshrine
因此，以太坊社区中总会有人说，哦，我们需要招架
this, we need to think about that, Ethereum should go in that direction or shouldn't go
这是我们需要考虑的，以太坊应该朝这个方向发展或不应该走
in that direction as well.
朝那个方向朝着。
There are legitimate reasons to try and scale back also the protocol development, let's
有合理的理由可以尝试减少协议制定，让我们
say.
说。
the main reason why we want to go in the direction of more updates and more protocol features
我们要朝着更多更新和更多协议功能的方向发展的主要原因
is because we consider that when something is in protocol it makes it credible so it's
是因为我们认为，当某些内容中存在协议时，它使其可信，因此
only it that gives a super power to the to the mechanism that we are trying to enshrine
只有它赋予我们试图赋予机制的超级力量
and so i wanted to question where is this coming from and how far should we go with it or how far
因此，我想质疑这是从哪里来的，我们应该走多远或多远
should the ethereum community go with that and so what should the protocol see like how much should
以太坊社区是否应该与之相处，那么该协议应该看到什么
we build in terms of features and services. So yeah, I encourage you to check out this post.
我们在功能和服务方面建立。是的，我鼓励您查看这篇文章。
But a brief TLDR is for me, how the protocol kind of gets that special power is that it's set up
但是简短的tldr对我来说是如何获得特殊权力的协议是如何设置的
first. So it's not like the primary object, the primary object that sits behind it is this
第一的。因此，它不像主要对象，其背后的主要对象是
diffuse community of people that I'm a part of, and you're also a part of,
我是我的一部分的人社区，您也是您的一部分
and this community is trying to set up the protocol so that it achieves goals in a way
这个社区正试图建立协议，以便以某种方式实现目标
that's more automated, but in a way that it reduces coordination costs. We all agree to
这是更加自动化的，但以降低协调成本的方式。我们都同意
participate in the protocol along certain rules that are
符合某些规则的协议
spelled out in the specification or in the client code that you run. So that gives the protocol a
在规范或您运行的客户端代码中拼写。因此，这给了协议
lot of power, having this community at the back. But the way it sort of goes from being that thing
有很多力量，将这个社区放在后面。但是它的方式从成为那东西
in the sky to an actual thing that runs on your computer is like you have validators and you have
在天空中，您的计算机上运行的实际内容就像您有验证器，并且有
two nodes that are supposed to do this work of running the protocol and running these services
两个节点应该从事运行协议并运行这些服务的工作
and so if the goal of the protocol is this decentralized provision of block space for
因此，如果协议的目的是该分散的块空间规定
users to achieve maximal welfare then you you want to question okay is that actually what's
用户要获得最大的福利，那么您想质疑的是，实际上是什么
happening so when you have validators that are untrusted that are very decentralized
发生的情况是，当您拥有不受信任的验证器时，这些验证者非常分散
potentially a large sale that you don't know the extent of. Do you actually achieve this?
您可能不知道的大型销售。您实际上实现了吗？
Or are there ways for people to deviate and to maybe extract more rent than they should?
还是人们可以偏离和提取比应有的租金更多的方法？
And so what do these validators do exactly? So I discussed that a bit. The consensus service is the
那么这些验证者到底做什么？所以我讨论了一些。共识服务是
kind of service that is there to give finality to the chain, make sure that we all agree on
有一种可以使链条终止的服务，请确保我们都同意
the state and the history of Ethereum and what's happened at the ledger. And then the block
以太坊的状态和历史以及分类帐发生的事情。然后块
construction service, in a sense, like the liveness, I think that it keeps adding more
从某种意义上说，建筑服务像Livices一样，我认为它不断增加更多
useful things, more user transactions, more ways for the users to do it. And there's a service
有用的事情，更多的用户交易，用户可以做的更多方法。还有一项服务
that's kind of very related to this block construction service, which is the protocol
这与此块建筑服务非常相关，这是协议
also tries to be neutral in terms of who can get on chain. And so you have this censorship
还试图在谁能搭上链子上保持中立。所以你有这个审查制度
present service that tries to say you know you shouldn't be like prevented from going on chain
目前试图说您知道您不应该阻止链条的服务
uh for reasons x y or z uh and so that's also important to to have this neutrality
嗯，出于X Y或Z uh的原因，因此对于这种中立也很重要
and so the problem now is okay you have a protocol with its great aims and and grand
因此，现在的问题是，您有一个协议，其伟大的目标和盛大
um plans uh but you also have the validators who are running it and so you you you're constantly
嗯，嗯，但是您还拥有正在运行它的验证者，所以您一直在不断
trying to figure out the games that the validators are going to play, or that they may deviate from
试图找出验证者将要玩的游戏，或者它们可能会偏离
things that the protocol would want them to do. And so the way that we try to control this,
协议希望他们做的事情。因此，我们试图控制这一点的方式，
or the way that we try to improve the situation, is I think in two ways. The first is to give more
或者我们试图改善情况的方式是两种方式。首先是给更多
introspection to the protocol, so allow it to see more things that are happening, like what
对协议的内省，因此让其看到更多正在发生的事情，例如
are validators doing, what are users doing, etc. And I'll give a specific example, because right
验证者在做什么，用户在做什么等。我将举一个特定的例子，因为正确
now it's a bit abstract and the second way is okay now that you get these signals that are credible
现在有点抽象，第二种方法还可以，因为您得到了这些可信的信号
like the protocol knows what's going on uh you can act upon this signal so you give a protocol like
就像该协议知道您可以在此信号上采取什么行动的情况，因此您提供了一个协议
ways to to to act upon this so you give it agency and uh and the main ways you do that is is with
采取行动的方法，以便您给予它代理和嗯，以及您所做的主要方式与
essentially crypto economic mechanisms of having uh rewards and penalties and trying
本质上是加密货币奖励和惩罚和尝试的经济机制
to shepherd the behavior of this uh emergent system in in the direction that it likes
为了朝着喜欢的方向朝着这个UH新兴系统的行为
So yeah, I know that the questions are happening in a separate chat room.
是的，我知道问题正在单独的聊天室中发生。
I'm not monitoring that, but if there's anything, feel free to stop me, Mario or Josh.
我不是在监视这一点，但是如果有的话，请随时阻止我，马里奥或乔什。
I'll try to make some poses as well.
我也会尝试做一些姿势。
Otherwise, no.
否则，没有。
Yeah, thank you.
是的，谢谢。
No questions so far.
到目前为止尚无问题。
Okay, cool.
好吧，很酷。
Right.
正确的。
So, okay, that was the abstract part.
所以，好的，那是抽象的部分。
Now I'll try to be a bit more concrete and to tell you, okay, what do we mean with these
现在我会尝试变得更具体，并告诉你，好吧，这是什么意思
services?
服务？
What are people actually doing?
人们实际在做什么？
What are the validators doing?
验证者在做什么？
And so the first one I want to talk about is the block reduction studies.
因此，我想谈的第一个是减少块研究。
So how do blocks get added on chain and what goes into these blocks essentially?
那么，如何将块添加到链中？这些块本质上是什么？
And so one mental model that I'm trying to argue for here is to think of validators as
因此，我想在这里争论的一种心理模型就是将验证者视为
the meeting point between the protocol on one side that regulates the supply of gas. So the protocol
一方面协议之间的会议点调节气体的供应。所以协议
says, you know, I am willing to supply some amount of block space that's consistent with general aims
说，你知道，我愿意提供一些与一般目标一致的块空间
of keeping the nodes light enough for people to run them and for the system to stay decentralized.
保持节点足够轻，以使人们可以运行它们并使系统保持分散。
And on the other side, you have users who have a demand for this block space. So the supply of gas
另一方面，您有对此块空间有需求的用户。所以气体的供应
on one side and the demand for gas on the other side. The demand is represented by transactions,
一侧以及对另一侧的气体需求。需求由交易代表，
so transactions come in and they're asking for gas and we're trying to allocate the best use of gas
所以交易来了，他们正在要求汽油，我们正在尝试最好地分配汽油
to these transactions. And the validators, they're really like the ones that sit in the middle and
这些交易。还有验证者，它们真的就像坐在中间的那些
that are provided with the responsibility, airdropped the responsibility of making that
所提供的责任，空调的责任是
allocation and what comes out of this is blocks. So, they decide what goes into the blocks and
分配以及从中出现的是块。因此，他们决定进入街区的原因
which transactions are being served. So it's not completely unconstrained, like they don't have...
正在提供哪些交易。因此，它并不是没有完全不受约束的，就像他们没有...
So first, there is the gas limit, of course, the protocol doesn't give them
因此，首先，当然有气体限制，协议没有给它们
infinite amounts of gas that they can just execute for the transactions to consume. But another
他们只能执行交易的无限气体。但是另一个
Another constraint that's now very important and that went online in August 2021 is EIP-1559.
现在非常重要的另一个约束，在2021年8月上网的是EIP-1559。
And so this is a fee market mechanism that essentially says the protocol is able to know
因此，这是一种收费市场机制，本质上说该协议能够知道
how much demand there is.
有多少需求。
So by demand, I mean like how much money people are willing to pay to get on chain.
因此，根据需求，我的意思是就像人们愿意为链条付出多少钱。
This signal comes to it credibly.
这个信号出现了。
And so it's going to mandate for the users that you have to pay at least this much to
因此，对于用户来说，您至少必须支付这笔费用
get on chain.
上链。
So before EIP-1559, there was no such thing.
因此，在EIP-1559之前，没有这样的事情。
The validator could just include any transaction they want, even a transaction that pays no
验证者只能包括他们想要的任何交易，甚至可以支付不支付的交易
fee, for instance.
例如，费用。
But after EIP-1559, you can think of it as almost like an Uber search pricing type of
但是在EIP-1559之后，您可以将其视为几乎就像Uber搜索定价类型
mechanism.
机制。
So when the demand is high, suddenly the protocol jacks up the prices, understands that, okay,
因此，当需求很高时，协议突然提高了价格，知道，好的，
there's many people waiting, there's a lot of demand, people are willing to pay.
有很多人在等待，需求很多，人们愿意付款。
So the minimum price that people need to pay to get on chain rises.
因此，人们需要支付的最低价格才能上涨。
The way we get this credible signal is essentially by having these double-sized blocks and saying
我们获得这些可信信号的方式本质上是通过拥有这些双重尺寸的块并说
that we want to target a half-full block.
我们想针对半满块。
And so we see if we are above target it means, okay, too many people want to go on chain,
因此，我们看到我们是否在目标之上，这意味着，好的，太多的人想继续链条，
so the price goes up according to the formula here.
因此，根据这里的公式，价格上涨。
And if not enough people want to go on chain, maybe because the price is too high, we reduce
如果没有足够的人愿意继续连锁，也许是因为价格太高，我们会减少
the price.
价格。
And over time, on average, we are going to be able to supply the target amount of gas.
随着时间的流逝，平均而言，我们将能够提供目标量。
And so it's set at 15 million.
因此，它设定为1500万。
So that's one constraint that the protocol has imposed.
因此，这是该协议实施的约束。
And it's it's a really clear example of this idea.
这是这个想法的一个非常明显的例子。
The protocol gets introspection of how much people are willing to pay for using it, like
该协议可以自省，愿意使用多少人来使用它，例如
people want to get on chain and it acts upon it by mandating this minimum payment for the user
人们想上连锁，它通过向用户授权这笔最低付款来对其进行行动
which has improved UX and has made the job of wallet much easier.
它改善了UX，使钱包的工作变得更加容易。
And so okay, we kind of also have this other thrust in it, like this other branch of things
好的，我们也有其他推力，就像其他事物的其他分支一样
we want to escape, right?
我们想逃脱，对吗？
We want to have more transactions.
我们希望有更多的交易。
So it's kind of nice,
所以有点很好，
but it doesn't do anything in terms of allowing more people
但这在允许更多人的角度没有做任何事情
to go on chain it just tries to provide good pricing
要继续链条，它只是试图提供良好的定价
or like objective pricing for them.
或为他们提供客观定价。
And so what we really want is then to maximize
因此，我们真正想要的就是最大化
the capacity of the system.
系统的容量。
And so the idea of the Diachrome community
因此，乔氏体社区的想法
that was to go into this world of centric roadmap.
那是进入这个中心路线图的世界。
So allow these L2s to become like the way that it scales.
因此，让这些L2S变得像缩放的方式一样。
And so what this means is before this EIP-4844
因此，这意味着在此EIP-4844之前
that came online just a month ago,
就在一个月前在线上
the protocol wasn't really making the distinction
该协议并不是真正的区别
between users like you and me who are just going
在像您和我这样的用户之间
to send transactions with a huge sum,
要以巨大的款项发送交易，
it's a swap or mini swap or something,
这是交换或迷你交换之类的东西，
and rollups who were like publishing all of this data
和像发布所有这些数据的汇总
on chain.
在链上。
So the protocol was kind of blind to that thing.
因此，该协议对那件事有些看不见。
And so now with the IP for it go forward,
因此，现在随着IP的前进，
what has actually happened is the idea that, okay,
实际发生的是，好的，好吧，
we're going to create like a special facility
我们将像特殊设施一样创建
for the rollups, which are almost like power users
对于汇总，几乎就像电力用户
to post their data.
发布他们的数据。
And the reason why it's a special facility
以及为什么它是特殊设施的原因
is that the data they post it doesn't really have
是他们发布的数据真的没有
the same dynamics as the data you and I post.
与您和我发布的数据相同的动态。
When I send a transaction,
当我发送交易时，
I use the call data to call the function
我使用呼叫数据来呼叫该功能
that needs to kind of stay in the history.
这需要留在历史上。
But for the roll-ups, what they really care about
但是对于卷起，他们真正关心的
is for the data to be widely available at some point
可以在某个时候广泛使用数据
but you don't really need to store it over time.
但是您实际上不需要随着时间的推移存储它。
And so that's what the special facility is doing.
这就是特殊设施正在做的事情。
And so here again, it's an example of
因此，在这里，这是一个例子
we are allowing the protocol to have more introspection.
我们允许该协议具有更多的内省。
Like we say, it's not just like these dumb users
就像我们说的那样，这不仅是这些愚蠢的用户
or retail users that are using you,
或正在使用您的零售用户
but there's also like these roll-ups
但是也有这些卷起
which have specific needs in terms of the services
在服务方面有特定需求
they want to use.
他们想使用。
And so we are going to create a very specific facility
因此，我们将创建一个非常具体的设施
for the Rolex to do that.
让劳力士这样做。
So now again, we have this new market
所以现在又有这个新市场
and we've kind of increased the ability for the protocol
我们已经提高了协议的能力
to serve distinct demands.
满足不同的要求。
Yeah, so that's exciting.
是的，这很令人兴奋。
um and so moving now to like let's say the the more difficult and esoteric topics of protocol
嗯，现在就可以说是说协议的更加困难和深奥的话题
uh proposal builder's passion yeah before yeah before we move on um got a nice question here
uh提案建造者的激情是的，在我们继续前进之前
uh from somebody in the discord uh referring to what you said about community setting goals for
嗯，来自不和谐中的某人，uh指的是您所说的关于社区设定目标的说法
for the protocol, do you feel that unbundling validator roles
对于协议，您是否认为解开验证器角色
into different sub-roles, like proposer, attester, delegator,
进入不同的子函数，例如提议者，入场者，代表们，
et cetera, would help the community to better exercise
et cetera，将帮助社区更好地运动
control over validators on the long term,
从长期来控制验证器，
or ensuring that validators act as the community would
或确保验证者作为社区的行为
want them to?
想要他们吗？
And yeah, would you give your thoughts on that?
是的，您会对此做出想法吗？
JAVIER D' Yeah, I can give some
哈维尔D'是的，我可以给一些
puts now, and I think over the course of this talk,
现在说，我认为在这次演讲过程中，
I will talk a bit more about unbundling specifically.
我将更多地谈论有关捆绑捆绑的更多信息。
But in a way, I do think it uses more control as a community.
但是在某种程度上，我确实认为它将更多的控制权作为一个社区。
And the reason is that when you're
原因是当你
trying to fit a very big object into a very specific door,
试图将非常大的物体装入非常特定的门，
it's just harder.
这很难。
So the ability to unbundle these different things
因此能够解开这些不同事物的能力
does, I think, amplify the control
我认为，会放大控制
that the community has on the protocols.
社区在协议上具有。
For instance, if we had said, we want
例如，如果我们说过，我们想要
to remain blind to roll-ups existing on Ethereum,
要对以太坊上存在的卷起视而不见，
we're not going to do anything special for them.
我们不会为他们做任何特别的事情。
We are not really, like we're staying at a point
我们不是真的，就像我们待在一个时刻
in this design space, but my opinion is very suboptimal.
在这个设计空间中，但我的看法非常最佳。
So by unbundling, like by creating these different gadgets
因此，通过捆绑，例如创建这些不同的小工具
and facilities, I think we do exercise this control
和设施，我认为我们确实行使此控制
and also allow ourselves to decentralize reactors
还可以让自己分散反应堆
that exist outside of the protocol.
在协议之外存在。
But maybe that point will be a bit clearer
但是也许这一点会更清楚
as I go through the slides.
当我浏览幻灯片时。
Cool, thank you.
酷，谢谢。
So it's a nice question also to have in mind as we go through all these different
因此，当我们经历所有这些不同的情况时，也要牢记这是一个很好的问题
levels.
水平。
Great, all right, looking forward to it.
很好，好的，期待它。
Good.
好的。
Yeah, so yes, speaking of control, so here I'm picturing what the app room kind of has
是的，是的，说到控制，所以在这里我想象的是应用程序房有什么
control over.
控制。
So it sees what the validators are doing to some extent, it sees the validators filling
因此，它看到了验证者在某种程度上在做什么，它看到了验证器填充
the blocks with more gas it sees the validators doing stuff on the consensus failure that
块带有更多气体的块看到验证者在共识失败时做事
i'll discuss in the next section and it it has the ability to give rewards and penalties to
我将在下一部分中讨论，它有能力给予奖励和罚款
these validators that's kind of how it keeps them in check it but it has also partial control over
这些验证者是如何使它们进行检查的一种验证者，但也有部分控制
the way that validators are building the blocks but not full control partial control because
验证者构建块但不能完全控制部分控制的方式，因为
of the ip1559 because of the gas limit for instance but it doesn't necessarily see everything
IP1559的原因是因为气体极限，但不一定会看到所有内容
that the validators are doing. In particular it doesn't see how the validators are sequencing
验证者正在做。特别是它看不到验证者如何测序
their blocks. So there's no rule in Ethereum in terms of you have to put this transaction first,
他们的街区。因此，以太坊没有规则，您必须将这笔交易放在首位，
this transaction second, etc. And that actually turned out to be an extremely valuable power
这笔交易第二等。实际上，这是极其有价值的力量
to have for validators, the power to sequence the block and to even insert their own transactions.
为了获得验证者，将块对块进行测序甚至插入自己的交易的权力。
and it's something through this power or the value of that power is what people refer to as MED,
这是通过这种力量或该力量的价值是人们所说的。
so maximum extractable value it's really the value that the validator can get from being
因此，最大可提取值实际上是验证者可以从存在的值
in control of the way that these blocks are being constructed and the way this control is exerted
控制这些块的构建方式以及该控制的方式
outside of the purview of the protocol. And so it was not even like the validators it was
在协议的权限之外。因此，它甚至都不喜欢验证者
the miners first in proof-of-work so when the miners figured out that okay this thing that
矿工首先是工作证明，所以当矿工弄清楚这一点时
I have has value, they soon figured out that okay what I could do is I'm going to maybe take
我有价值
part in the construction of my block but I'm also going to mostly delegate the responsibility of
一部分是建造我的街区，但我也将主要承担
finding out what is this most valuable block to a network of entities that are known as builders
找出对被称为建筑商的实体网络的最有价值的块是什么
and that will try and entice me to choose the blocks that they're building. So I will say you
这将试图吸引我选择他们构建的块。所以我会说你
you know, I'm not as very, I'm not very good at making the block, but you guys are the builders.
你知道，我不是很擅长制作街区，但你们是建筑商。
And so try and tell me how much you think you can give me back in terms of value. And so you
因此，请尝试告诉我您认为您可以在价值方面回馈我多少。所以你
have this auction happening between the validators and the builders, and the validators are choosing
在验证者和构建者之间进行此拍卖，验证者正在选择
which block to choose, to use as a result of this auction. What's interesting is that all of this is
这次拍卖会选择哪个块。有趣的是所有这些都是
really happening completely outside of the view of the Ethereum protocol. So it really does not know
在以太坊协议的视野之外，确实发生了。所以它真的不知道
that the validators are delegating this pretty core activity to the builders. And when I say
验证者将这一漂亮的核心活动委派给了构建者。当我说
this, I don't mean all validators. 90% of the blocks today are built from this external network
这并不是说所有验证者。当今90％的块是由这个外部网络构建的
of builders, but there are still 10% that are not. But it's a very significant shift in the
在建筑商中，但仍然没有10％的人。但这是一个非常重大的转变
it's a political economy of who are the parties acting on the period and what are the value
这是一个政治经济学，谁是该时期行事的当事人
flows between them.
他们之间的流动。
And so the natural question has been, well, should we move forward the boundary of the
因此，自然的问题是，如果我们向前迈进
protocol?
协议？
Should we try and get a sense of what's happening out there and potentially even enshrine parts
我们是否应该尝试了解正在发生的事情，甚至可能占领零件
of this delegation so that we resume control of this?
这个代表团以便我们恢复对此的控制？
So now I want to show it. These are images from a post that I'm working on, but I've
所以现在我想展示它。这些是我正在从事的帖子中的图像，但是我已经
not finished it quite yet, so it's the first time I'm presenting it. But yeah, I'm trying
还没有完成，所以这是我第一次介绍它。但是，我正在尝试
to give here the idea of what exactly is the protocol giving the validators, when it's
在此处给出一个关于协议给验证者到底是什么的想法，
giving it the right to make a block. And so what I'm saying here is the Ethereum protocol
赋予它制作障碍的权利。所以我在这里说的是以太坊协议
originates these rights and gives validator the right to propose a block, a block that
启动这些权利，并赋予验证者提出一个块的权利，一个块，一个块
contains consensus data and the execution payload.
包含共识数据和执行有效载荷。
So the consensus data is all the stuff that attestation, finality, etc.
因此，共识数据是证明，最终性等的所有内容。
I'll touch upon this later.
稍后我会谈谈。
And the execution payload is really the list of transactions.
执行有效载荷实际上是交易列表。
But that's the thing that the validators today are trying to get built by someone else.
但这就是当今验证者试图由其他人建造的东西。
What we are observing today is Mere Boost, the off-chain network of builders, or rather
我们今天所观察到的只是Boost，构建者的链链网络，或者更确切地说
out-of-protocol network of builders, that the validators are engaging to make, or to
构建者的企业外网络，验证者正在参与或
sequence, or to build blocks on their behalf.
顺序，或代表他们建立块。
What happens here is the Ethereum protocol gives the validator this proposing right,
这里发生的是以太坊协议为验证器提供了此建议的权利，
The validator creates this new right, which is the right to sequence the block or to build it,
验证者创建了这一新权利，这是对块进行测序或构建块的权利，
and offers that right to the builder. So it says to the builder,
并向建筑商提供该权利。所以它对建筑商说
you can make the block on my behalf, you can tell me what to put in there.
您可以代表我制作街区，可以告诉我要放在那里。
The validator will still remain the proposer, that's the proposer-builder separation.
验证者仍将仍然是建议者，这就是提议者建设者的分离。
I'm picturing it on the side, the validator pretends the block they made was theirs,
我在一边想象它，验证者假装他们制造的块是他们的块，
But essentially, the builder is the one that's building it.
但从本质上讲，建筑商是正在建造它的人。
And so the first idea to try and enshrine
因此，第一个尝试招架的想法
some of these mechanisms in the protocol is EPBS,
协议中的其中一些机制是EPB，
so EnshrinePBS, and more specifically,
因此，EnshrinePB，更具体地说，
it's what I call blockOptionEPBS.
这就是我所说的Blockoptionepbs。
So here, the protocol gives to the validator
因此，在这里，协议给了验证者
or the beacon proposer the proposing rights,
或信标提议者提出权利，
And then the validator is going to be able to commit
然后验证者将能够提交
to an execution proposer that is going to reveal
要揭示的执行建议者
the execution payload in a second step.
执行有效载荷在第二步中。
So we are moving from the situation here
所以我们正在从这里的情况转移
where everything happened in one step,
一切都在一步中发生的地方，
the validator proposes this big block
验证者提出了这个大块
that contains consensus data and execution payload
其中包含共识数据和执行有效载荷
to a protocol that moves in two steps.
到分为两个步骤的协议。
One where the validator reveals this beacon block that
验证器揭示此信标块的地方
contains the consensus data.
包含共识数据。
And that also contains a commitment
而且还包含承诺
to someone who will build the block for the execution
给将要构建执行块的人
payload for them.
他们的有效载荷。
So what it will be execution proposal.
因此，将是执行建议。
And in this block auction, it is yes,
在这个块拍卖中，是的，
the commitment is also to the specific contents of the blocks.
该承诺也是对块的特定内容。
So the builders tell the validator,
因此，建筑商告诉验证者，
I will be this block for you that has this transaction route.
我将为您提供此交易路线的障碍。
So like a hash of the transaction.
因此，就像交易的哈希一样。
So the validator does not know what the what the block contains.
因此，验证器不知道块包含的内容。
They only know like a hash
他们只知道像哈希
they will be coming to that.
他们会来的。
And by this commitment, now the protocol will expect in the second step
通过这一承诺，现在协议将在第二步中期望
for the execution proposal to reveal the execution payload.
对于执行提案以揭示执行有效载荷。
And so that's kind of nice because, for instance,
所以这很好，因为
if the builder goes offline for any reason,
如果建造者出于任何原因离线，
or the execution proposer goes offline for any reason,
或执行建议者出于任何原因脱机，
we can still have the beacon proposer
我们仍然可以有信标提议者
containing the consensus data,
包含共识数据，
which is not the case today.
今天不是这样。
So it has a failure at any point in that interaction,
因此，它在该互动中的任何时刻都有失败，
the whole block is lost.
整个障碍都丢失了。
So when we miss a block,
因此，当我们错过一个街区时
we miss both the consensus data and the execution payload.
我们错过了共识数据和执行有效载荷。
Another thing that's nice is that the commitment
另一件事是承诺
the beacon proposer is making to the execution proposer it's kind of guaranteed by the protocol
信标提案者正在为执行提案者做出协议保证
so if there's a promise of a payment uh and that and if this promise is become canonical so if the
因此，如果有付款的承诺，那么如果这个承诺成为规范，则
beacon block it goes on chain and it's attested to uh with enough weight uh then it's on really
信标块它沿着连锁
on the builder's uh shoulders to propose the the block in time so what i'm noting here as well is
在建筑商的UH肩膀上，及时提出了块，所以我在这里指的是
is that even if we have this enshrined proposer builder
即使我们有这个提议者建造者
separation, it's still possible for the beacon proposer
分离，信标提议者仍然有可能
to liaise with the execution proposer using MEV-BOOST.
使用MEV-Boost与执行建议者联络。
So it's still possible to kind of bypass
因此，仍然有可能绕过
this whole protocol infrastructure
整个协议基础架构
and use MEV-BOOST.
并使用Mev-Boost。
So it's not really like EIP-1559 in the sense of, OK,
因此，从某种意义上说，这并不是真的像EIP-1559
now there's this thing that you have to do,
现在您必须做这个事情，
this price you have to pay, because you kind of
您必须支付的这个价格，因为您有点
are able to bypass it.
能够绕过它。
But it might still be good in terms of providing a decent trust minimized option for the beacon proposer,
但是，在提供一个不错的信托最小化的选择方面，这可能仍然很好
so validators, to get into contracts with the execution proposers and the builders.
因此，验证者与执行提案者和建筑商签订合同。
And so I think when people talk about EPBS, they mostly mean this version.
因此，我认为当人们谈论EPB时，它们主要是指这个版本。
There is a version that's interesting as well, which is slot auction EPBS.
也有一个有趣的版本，即插槽拍卖EPB。
And in this version of EPBS, the beacon proposer only commits to who will propose the execution
在此版本的EPB中，Beacon提案者只致力于谁提出执行
payload.
有效载荷。
So it only commits to the pseudonym or the public key of the execution proposer, but
因此，它仅承诺化名或执行建议者的公钥，但是
it doesn't commit to the contents of the block.
它不承担块的内容。
And so when the execution proposer kind of wins this ticket to make the execution payload,
因此
might still realize okay I could resell the building rights to someone else. So here what
可能仍然会意识到好的，我可以将建筑权转售给别人。所以在这里
I'm depicting with the dotted line is that again all of these interactions are kind of optional.
我用虚线描绘的是，所有这些交互都是可选的。
So the beacon proposer would very well give themselves the execution proposing rights
因此，标准提案者将很好地赋予自己执行权利的权利
and then listen to offers from a builder. They could also bypass the system and have like
然后收听建筑商的提议。他们也可以绕过系统，并且有
a second system to decide who the execution proposer should be.
第二个系统来决定执行建议者应该是谁。
What I'm trying to convey here is that it's a little more flexibility
我想在这里传达的是，它更灵活
in terms of you don't have to convince me about what's in your blog
就您而言，您不必说服我关于您的博客中的内容
and you don't have to commit to the contents of your blog at the time
而且，您不必当时对博客的内容承诺
where you're making this bid.
您要在哪里出价。
You can just buy the rights to make the execution payload
您只需购买权利以进行执行有效载荷
and then you may be able to or you may want to resale
然后您可能能够或您想转售
the bidding rights on your side.
您身边的竞标权。
And the reason I'm talking about this is because it starts to decouple
我谈论这个的原因是因为它开始解散
a bit more the beacon proposer with the execution proposer. So the beacon proposer is still
与执行建议者一起使用的信标提案者更多。所以信标提案者仍然
responsible for choosing who the execution proposer will be, but it's not the end-all
负责选择执行建议者是谁，但这并不是全部
be-all for committing to the block contents. So just as a quick comparison between the two,
全力投入块内容。因此，就像两者之间的快速比较一样，
in block-action EPBS, the beacon proposer is committing both to who the builder will be and
在BOCK-ACTION EPB中，Beacon提案者既致力于建造者的身份和
also to the to the block contents uh whereas in the slot auction epbs the beacon proposer is only
同样在块中的内容uh，而在插槽拍卖会epb中，信标建议者仅为
committing to the identity of the execution proposal and not to the block content at this
致力于执行提案的身份，而不是在此任务块内容
time and that gives a little bit more flexibility to the to the execution proposal um okay yeah um
时间，这给执行提案提供了更大的灵活性，嗯，是的
So these are two proposals for EPBS, it's two variations of EPBS, but on the same topic of
因此，这是EPB的两个建议，这是EPB的两个变体，但在同一主题上
trying to decouple the execution part and the consensus part of the protocol, there's another
试图将执行部分和协议的共识部分解除，还有另一个
proposal that I think you've heard about when Mike and Dom came on the call here, which is
我认为您何时听说Mike和Dom何时在这里通话，这是
execution tickets. And now you can think of execution tickets as, okay, validators are no
执行票。现在，您可以将执行票考虑为，好的，验证者没有
longer choosing who the execution proposer is. The execution proposer is going to be chosen by
选择执行建议者是谁。执行建议者将由
a market that we call the execution ticket market that is created in protocol and that offers
我们称为在协议中创建的执行票务市场的市场，并提供
tickets to people who want it. So this market is permissionless, anybody can come to the market and
想要的人的门票。因此，这个市场是无许可的，任何人都可以进入市场，
buy a ticket and this ticket eventually redeems for them to become an execution proposer. So
购买票，这张票最终兑换为他们成为执行建议者。所以
So again, we have the same separation
所以再次，我们有相同的分离
between the proposing right and the building right.
在提议右边和建筑物右边之间。
So if I own a ticket that gives me eventually the right
因此，如果我拥有一张票，最终给了我正确的权利
to propose a block, I am still able to outsource
要提出一个块，我仍然能够外包
or to resell the building rights that come with that ticket.
或转售该票随附的建筑物权利。
And that means we might still see stuff like MEV Boost
这意味着我们可能仍然会看到Mev Boost之类的东西
and the relay infrastructure in that model.
以及该模型中的继电器基础架构。
So what's nice and what I depict under the arrow
那么，什么好，我在箭下描绘了什么
the bottom here is that because this market is essentially a protocol gadget, we have introspection
底部是，由于这个市场本质上是一个协议小工具，所以我们有内省
over who comes to the market and how much they are willing to pay. And that introspection is credible,
关于谁来市场以及他们愿意付出多少。而且内省是可信的，
or at least we can make it credible. And if it's credible it means we can capture the value that
或者至少我们可以使其可信。如果是可信的，则意味着我们可以捕获
people are paying when they are coming to the market. So here's the distinction between
人们进入市场时正在付款。所以这是
slot auction epbs and execution tickets um we can do this with it market because all of this
老虎机拍卖EPB和执行票，我们可以在IT市场上做到这一点，因为所有这些
infrastructure is really entranian protocol in the slot auction epbs we can't do the burn just
基础架构实际上是插槽拍卖EPB中我们不能仅仅烧伤的特兰尼亚协议
like naive we can't say oh you know whatever amount you're getting here as a beacon composer
像幼稚一样，我们不能说哦，你知道你以灯塔作曲家的身份到达这里
we are going to burn it because the beacon proposer can totally misrepresent the value
我们要燃烧它，因为信标提议者可以完全歪曲价值
uh of the bid they received for for the person to to become an execution proposal and so the
他们收到的竞标是为了使该人成为执行提案，因此
ability to say you know it's only going to give you as a validator the beacon proposing rights
能够说您知道它只会给您作为验证者的信标提出权利的验证者
and the addiction proposing rights are going to be given to this protocol structure called
并且提出的成瘾权将被赋予该协议结构称为
the efficient ticket market that allows you to to create this this burn and this
高效的门票市场，使您能够创造这种燃烧，这是
value value capture and this then really also decouples the the roles of the validator as
价值捕获，然后确实将验证器的角色分解为
as someone who's here to provide the consensus data
作为在这里提供共识数据的人
and the execution proposer as someone who's here
执行提案者是在这里的人
to make the blocks and sequence them, et cetera.
制作块并对其进行排序，等等。
Cool, so yeah, I know it's a bit a lot
酷，是的，我知道这有点
and I think spending probably more time
而且我认为花更多的时间
on this will be helpful.
对此会有所帮助。
I'm hoping to publish the post soon enough,
我希望尽快发表该帖子，
but I hope it's at least a nice insight.
但是我希望这至少是一个很好的见解。
To sum up where we are, we started with this picture of the validators providing the consensus
为了总结我们所处的位置，我们从提供共识的验证者的图片开始
service and the block construction service, and we ended up at this picture where now
服务和块建筑服务，我们最终在这张照片中
we have a network of beacon proposers, so the validators in our system who are responsible
我们有一个信标建议者网络，因此系统中负责的验证者
for this consensus service, and a network of execution proposers who are responsible
对于此共识服务，以及负责的执行建议者网络
for this block-constructed service.
对于此块构造的服务。
The issue now is that, well,
现在的问题是，好吧，
we know the builders are typically more centralized,
我们知道建筑商通常更集中，
so these execution proposals should also,
因此，这些执行建议也应该
we should expect them to be centralized
我们应该期望他们被集中
and sophisticated entities.
和复杂的实体。
And these entities are now responsible, in a way,
这些实体现在在某种程度上负责
for providing the censorship resistance of the chain,
为了提供链的审查阻力，
which is not necessarily the best solution.
这不一定是最好的解决方案。
I think it would be more comfortable if the validators,
我认为如果验证者，
where everyone's providing that service.
每个人都提供该服务的地方。
And the reason why is because
原因是因为
like we want this decentralization of the operators
就像我们想要运营商的权力下放
because that allows the system as a whole
因为这允许系统整体
to express a wider set of preferences.
表达更广泛的首选项。
So that means when you have like this
所以这意味着当你有这样的时候
very decentralized set of validators
非常分散的验证器集
and when the block is being made,
当制造块时，
the validators would include transactions
验证者将包括交易
that others for instance dislike.
例如，其他人不喜欢。
The validators are outsourcing the duty
验证者正在外包职责
making a block to other people, we're kind of losing the benefit of having a well-decentralized
与他人建立障碍，我们有点失去了一个详细的占领的好处
set of operators in the first place, because the people we are outsourcing this utility to,
首先，一组运营商，因为我们正在将这个效用的人外包给
they may not be as decentralized as the validator set. And it's the same thing in consensus,
它们可能不像验证器集那样分散。在共识中是同一件事，
like we also really care about having a validator set that's decentralized, because
就像我们也真的在乎拥有分散的验证器集，因为
we want them to be decorrelated, and that creates a lot of resilience in the system.
我们希望它们与之脱离相关，并在系统中产生很多弹性。
So, yeah, allow me to say a little more about this last point.
所以，是的，请允许我对最后一点说更多。
Before that, just checking if there's any questions before I move on.
在此之前，只需检查我继续前进之前是否有任何问题。
Yeah, I have a question around the execution tickets and block proposals.
是的，我对执行票和阻止提案有一个疑问。
So with execution tickets, does that change the frequency a particular validator has to
因此，使用执行票，是否会改变特定验证器必须的频率
the rights to like proposal block or what is the mechanism for you know uh redeeming and execution
喜欢提案块的权利或您知道赎回和执行的机制是什么
ticket yeah that's a good question and it's something that's i would say it's a bit up in
票是的，这是一个很好的问题，我会说这有点
the air like there is uh an exit a proposal written by uh justin and mike uh which has this
空气像UH Justin和Mike UH撰写的提案一样
idea of okay there is this market that exists and you can go to the market and buy the tickets to
好的想法存在这个市场，您可以去市场并购买门票
become an execution proposer. So that means as a validator, if I want to propose a payload,
成为执行建议者。因此，这意味着作为验证者，如果我想提出有效载荷，
so propose a set of transactions, I have to go myself to the market and buy one of these tickets.
因此，建议一组交易，我必须自己去市场并购买其中一张门票。
So by default, so if I compare with the slot auction EPBS for instance, in EPBS by default,
因此，默认情况下，因此，如果我与插槽拍卖EPB进行比较，例如，在EPB中，
the validator is the execution proposer, like they can give to themselves the right to propose
验证者是执行建议者，就像他们可以赋予自己的权利
the execution payload but in execution ticket it's no longer the case by default the validator
执行有效载荷，但在执行票中，默认情况下不再是这种情况
is only the decon proposer and not the execution proposer and and when i say okay you need to go
只是Decon提议者，而不是执行建议者，当我说好的时，您需要去
to market and buy a ticket uh this go to market there's been like some some thoughts around this
销售和购买门票，嗯，这是一个上市的东西，对此有一些想法
so in the proposal by mike and justin uh imagine a market as almost like an amm an automated market
因此，在Mike和Justin Uh的提案中，想象一个市场几乎就像AMM自动市场
maker that just has a supply of tickets and people can just go to the AMM and buy a ticket from it,
只有门票供应的制造商，人们可以去AMM并从中购买票，
so it's an autonomous structure. But I think there's still a lot of questions on what are
因此，这是一个自主结构。但是我认为关于什么还有很多问题
the exact mechanics of this and how to operationalize it on-chain. So, when I want to
此的确切机制以及如何在链上操作它。所以，当我想
buy a ticket, do I make a transaction that goes in one of the execution payloads or is that a
购买票，我要做一次在执行有效载荷之一中进行的交易还是
transaction that lives in the consensus layer and who includes that transaction. So all of
生活在共识层以及包括该交易的人。全部
these I think are kind of unsettled questions that we need definitely a lot more thinking on.
我认为这些是一个不安的问题，我们绝对需要更多的思考。
Cool. If we want to maybe just pause for one moment, the person who asked that question
凉爽的。如果我们想停下来一会儿，问这个问题的人
is typing right now, so maybe they have my follow-up, but give it just a moment.
现在正在打字，所以也许他们有我的后续行动，但请稍等一下。
So, the follow-up is, so offline validators and double voting would then be slash retroactively
因此，后续措施是，因此离线验证者和双投票将被追溯砍伐
with the execution tickets?
有执行票吗？
I think it would kind of stay the same.
我认为这会保持不变。
It would look, from the validator side it would look pretty much what they are doing
看起来，从验证者一方看，它看起来几乎可以
today, except when they make blocks, it wouldn't include the execution payload.
今天，除非它们制作块，它将不包括执行有效载荷。
That would be somebody else doing that.
那将是其他人这样做的。
And so if a validator was, for instance, proposing two beacon blocks at the same
因此，例如，如果验证器是在同一提议的两个信标块
height, or if a validator was making conflicting routes that are slashable,
高度，或者如果验证者正在制作矛盾的路线，则
they would be slashed according to the same mechanics that take place today.
根据今天发生的相同机制，它们将被削减。
So another validator would include a proof of why validator A needs to be slashed.
因此，另一个验证器将包括一个证明验证器A需要被削减的证明。
That proof would be contained in the beacon block.
该证明将包含在信标块中。
So it really just separates out the, what you call the block today that has this beacon part and this execution part into sub blocks or partial blocks that are delivered in different moments.
因此，它实际上只将其分开，您称之为标准部分的块，该执行部分分为子块或部分块，这些块或部分块在不同的时刻交付。
But from the slashing perspective it's pretty much the same.
但是从削减的角度来看，这几乎是相同的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right.
好的。
Cool.
凉爽的。
So really what I want to address here is what is the role of validators now?
那么，我在这里要解决的问题是验证者现在的作用是什么？
Why they delegated the role of constructing the execution payload to someone else, and
他们为什么将构建执行有效载荷构建给他人的作用以及
if we if we do move to like this execution ticket work or this validator proposal separation
如果我们确实喜欢此执行票务工作或此验证提案分离
yeah it's it's a very big change so let's look at what else we can think about in terms of
是的，这是一个很大的变化，所以让我们看看我们还能考虑什么
unbundling or in terms of understanding the different roads that the protocol wants to
解开或了解协议想要的不同道路
to provide um so the content service is like very critical um the first
提供UM，因此内容服务就像第一个非常关键的UM
Even that you can kind of understand it as different mechanisms that are put together.
即便如此，您也可以将其理解为将其组合在一起的不同机制。
The first one is LMD ghost, so that's the fork choice rule, but that tells you at any
第一个是LMD Ghost，所以这是叉选择规则，但这告诉您任何
point of time what is the current head of the chain.
时间点是什么链的当前头。
You have this chain that is continuously growing, people can add blocks even when you don't
您拥有这个链条不断成长的链，即使您不这样做，人们也可以添加块
have finality, and so you need this fork choice rule to understand what's the current state
具有最终性，因此您需要此叉子选择规则才能了解当前状态是什么
the network and the head of the chain. You have a second service which is CasperFFG which finalizes
网络和链的头部。您有第二份服务是Casperffg，该服务最终确定
the block so it's mechanisms of two further validators have to finalize like these epoch
该块因此，这是两个进一步验证器的机制，必须像这些时期那样完成
boundaries and then once it's final yeah only like a major safety event can happen for the
边界，然后是最终的界限，是的，只有一个重大安全事件才能发生
finality to be undone or to be conflicted. And then the third thing is when you take part in
终结或矛盾的终结性。然后第三件事是您参加
this consensus service you have to keep adding blocks to register new consensus data. So for
此共识服务您必须继续添加块才能注册新的共识数据。所以
instance people casting their finality votes in CasperFFG or giving weights to blocks according
实例人们在Casperffg中投票或对块进行权重
to the LMD ghost for choice rule. So you have like these three different things that you're
到LMD幽灵以获取选择规则。所以你喜欢这三件事
kind of taking part of when you are signing up for that for that service.
当您为该服务注册时，有点参与其中。
So, yeah, the world, according to the Ethereum protocol, or the world of validation and people
因此，是的，根据以太坊协议或验证世界和人民的世界
coming in to become validators, it's actually pretty small.
进入验证器，它实际上很小。
So, the Ethereum protocol understands that people are depositing if, so when they do
因此，以太坊协议知道人们正在存入，因此当他们这样做时
that, when they deposit 32 if, they declare, I want to sign up to become a validator, I
那就是，当他们存入32时，如果他们声明，我想注册成为验证者，我
want to sign up to provide this consensus service.
想要注册以提供此共识服务。
And sometimes people will go so they come out of everything and if your protocol only
有时人们会去，所以他们会从所有事物中出来，如果您的协议只有
has this viewer, okay, I'm getting a deposit of 32 if, and sometimes the deposits are coming
有这个观众吗，好吧，我得到的32个存款
out, and people are leaving the service.
外出，人们正在离开服务。
And so why do we actually need people to make these deposits?
那么，为什么我们实际上需要人们制作这些存款呢？
Why do we need this 32 if in the first place, so I'm really going into the, let's say, the
为什么首先需要这个32，所以我真的要去
rationale of proof-of-stake, we want people to come and give us this take, because we want to
有利于证明的理由，我们希望人们来给我们这个看法，因为我们想
be able, as a protocol or as a community, to say we have a credible commitment to providing good
作为协议或社区，我们可以说我们有可靠的承诺
service, to providing good quality of service. So the protocol can make statements such as
服务，提供优质的服务。因此协议可以做出诸如
if a finality or if a safety fault happens, if finality happens in two different places that are
如果最终性或安全性发生故障，如果在两个不同的地方发生最终性
are conflicted, then I can make the credible commitment that many billions of dollars are
有冲突，然后我可以做出可靠的承诺，即数十亿美元
going to be lost.
会迷路。
We have this property because we have accountability and we have slashing, so we know that it varies
我们之所以拥有此属性，是因为我们有责任制并且我们正在削减，所以我们知道它会有所不同
in safety for the functionality.
在功能上安全。
This is a guarantee we can make.
这是我们可以做出的保证。
And so, in a way, the protocol is an actor that demands capital, so that demands people
因此，在某种程度上，协议是需要资本的演员，因此要求人们
to bring stake to it so that it can make that commitment. But of course, when people bring
将股份带给它，以便可以做出这一承诺。但是当然，当人们带来
capital, there are many incentives for you to try and free your capital. So, when you stake,
资本，有许多激励措施可以尝试释放您的资本。所以，当你赌注时，
you kind of lock up that money, but capital tends to want to be free, it wants to be reutilized,
您有点锁定这笔钱，但是资本倾向于想要自由，它希望被重新充满活力，
it wants to be maximized in terms of its efficiency. And so, that is why we've seen
它希望以其效率最大化。因此，这就是为什么我们看到的
seen the growth of liquid staking protocols that allow you to bring your capital to stake,
看到液体含有协议的增长，使您能够利用资本，
but also have a liquid representation of it that allows you to still participate and still
但还具有液体代表，使您仍然可以参与并且仍然
have activities with your capital.
与您的资本一起进行活动。
So make the most out of the stake that you have.
因此，充分利用您拥有的木桩。
And so what's interesting here is that the statement above of if x happens, why billions
因此，这里有趣的是，上面的陈述是X发生的，为什么数十亿
dollars are lost it doesn't really specify who's dollars and so when i give my stake to someone
美元损失它并没有真正指定谁的美元，所以当我将股份交给某人时
who stakes on my behalf the protocol doesn't really see that and it doesn't know that okay
谁代表我赌注该协议并没有真正看到它，也不知道还可以
it's not barnaby's fault that the safety fault has happened it's barnaby who delegated to someone who
安全错误发生的是巴纳比（Barnaby）是巴拿比（Barnaby）
made that uh that fault happens but this is kind of like not existent and so and so the world
使那个错误发生了，但这是不存在的，所以世界
outside of Ethereum it's actually much more complicated than Ethereum thinks it is.
在以太坊之外，它实际上比以太坊认为的要复杂得多。
You have this long chain of intermediation where if I'm a staker and I want to stake
您有这么长的中间链
but not directly participate in the validation, I'm going to give my if to a deposit contract
但不直接参与验证，我将把我的if交给存款合同
of a liquid staking protocol who's going to add that if into a pool and then allocate the if to
液体含有协议的规定，如果将其添加到池中，然后将IF分配给
node operators who are going to validate on my behalf to the Ethereum protocol. And so
将代表我的以太坊协议来验证的节点操作员。所以
all of this infrastructure is really kind of like hidden, it doesn't exist in the eyes of the
所有这些基础架构真的很隐藏，它在眼中不存在
Ethereum protocol. And so really the people or the entities that are kind of treating with or
以太坊协议。因此，实际上的人或实体正在治疗或
or providing the service to the FUN protocol
或为娱乐协议提供服务
are these node operators.
这些节点运算符。
And so trying to understand who are these node operators
因此，试图了解这些节点操作员是谁
or who are these protocol service providers,
或这些协议服务提供商是谁
what we see today is really two classes of providers.
我们今天看到的实际上是两类提供商。
So there are those that are typically called solo operators.
因此，有些通常称为独奏运营商。
So I would say, or I would define them as people
所以我会说，否则我会将它们定义为人
who are a priori untrusted.
先验不受信任的人。
So we don't know who they are exactly.
因此，我们不知道他们是谁。
They don't come with some kind of ex-ante reputation
他们不带来某种前声誉
that tells me whether they are trustworthy
那告诉我他们是否值得信赖
or whether they're malicious
还是他们是恶意的
or whether they're going to do a good job as operators.
或者他们是否要作为运营商做得很好。
So you can think of living room validators,
因此，您可以想到客厅验证者
solo stakers who are both running their own operations
既有自己运营的独奏
and using their own capital to stake.
并利用自己的资本来利用。
And on the other side, you have these professional operators
另一方面，您有这些专业运营商
which are pretty trusted.
这是非常值得信赖的。
they can think of registered companies, big staking providers, like the big names you see.
他们可以想到注册公司，大型股份提供商，就像您看到的大人物一样。
And so when you give your stake to them, you kind of know that it comes with a trusted
因此，当您将自己的股份交给他们时，您就会知道它带有可信赖的
reputation. This is like a very black and white kind of distinction, but it's in truth it's not
名声。这就像一种非常黑白的区别，但实际上不是
that binary. So it's more like you have a credible signal that maybe you learn over time of whether
那个二进制。因此，这更像是您有一个可信的信号，也许您会随着时间的流逝而学习是否是否
of a pretty untrusted operator becomes more trusted.
一个非常不信任的操作员变得更加信任。
And this valuable signal may be learned by protocols.
该有价值的信号可以通过协议来学习。
And so in particular, it's taking protocols,
特别是，它正在采用协议，
they may be able to employ like a mixture of both types.
他们可能会像两种类型的混合物一样使用。
So we're seeing for instance,
所以我们看到，例如
Lido onboarding some solo operators,
Lido登上一些独奏操作员，
we see liquid-staking protocols that rocket pool,
我们看到了液体储存协议，这些协议是火箭池，
which are mostly composed of solo operators that stake.
其中主要由股份的独奏运营商组成。
So I want to discuss a little bit some of these constructions now.
因此，我现在想讨论其中一些结构。
So looking at the rocket pool model, the operator, so the person who's actually performing
因此，查看Rocket Pool模型，操作员，因此实际上表现的人
the service to the protocol, so like the consensus service, can be a solo-staker. And to do that,
协议的服务，因此像共识服务一样，可以成为独奏者。为此，
the solo operator only needs to put some ifs as collaterals. And then the delegator,
独奏操作员只需要将一些IF放置为抵押品。然后是代表们，
So people who want to stake but don't want to perform the service,
因此，想要股权但不想执行服务的人，
or who don't want to run a node and become validators themselves,
或者不想运行节点并自己成为验证器的人，
send their stake to this operator and kind of fill the remainder.
将他们的股份发送给该操作员，并填补其余部分。
So I think in RocketPool, the operator can put up 8 ETH,
因此，我认为在Rocketpool中，操作员可以提出8个ETH，
and the delegators can then fill up the rest with 24 ETH,
然后，代表们可以用24 ETH填充其余的
and the operator then stakes both on their own account,
然后，操作员都以自己的帐户为单位
as well as on the account of the delegators.
以及代表人的帐户。
So the idea for the operator to put their own money on the line is really to align the incentives and for them to say,
因此，运营商将自己的钱投入线上的想法确实是为了使激励措施保持一致，并使他们说，
okay, you have to do a good job because otherwise your own money will be lost first.
好的，您必须做得很好，因为否则您自己的钱将首先丢失。
So if you get slashed as a RocketPool operator, the first money that gets lost is yours,
因此，如果您被猛击为Rocketpool操作员，那么丢失的第一笔钱就是您的
and then the money of the delegators if necessary.
然后，如有必要，代表人的钱。
So that's a good system.
所以这是一个很好的系统。
allows you to onboard untrusted operators into the operations of like,
使您可以加入未经信任的操作员进入类似的操作，
uh, liquid-staking protocols, but still it's not the most, uh, capital
呃，液体储存协议，但仍然不是最多的，呃，资本
efficient way of going about it.
有效的方法。
So when you don't have this trust in the operator, um, you're going to have to
因此，当您对操作员没有这种信任时，嗯，您将不得不
require some kind of either collateral or more cost infrastructure to, to, to
需要某种抵押品或更多成本基础设施才能
ensure that, okay, they are credible operators, they are not going to, to
确保，好的，他们是可信的操作员，他们不会去
rug the delegators. And so the capital efficiency and the cost pressure kind of directives mean that
地毯代表们。因此，资本效率和成本压力的指令意味着
today the liquid stacking protocols do rely a lot on professional operators. So when the professional
如今，液体堆叠协议确实依赖于专业运营商。所以当专业人士
operator comes with like reputation, that's virtual money on the line, but it makes the
运营商带有声誉，这是虚拟的金钱，但这使得
capital efficiency of the other protocol significantly greater.
另一个协议的资本效率明显更大。
And so there was this idea in the Ethereum community, some researchers have been talking
因此，以太坊社区有这个想法，一些研究人员一直在谈论
about it, it's the idea of, okay, if there is this problem of trust between operators
关于它，这是，如果运营商之间存在这个信任问题的想法
who may be interested and delegators who are delegating to them, perhaps we can resolve
可能有兴趣的人和正在委派他们的代表人，也许我们可以解决
the problem of trust by saying only the operator is slashable.
仅说操作员可以削减信任的问题。
So in RocketPool, everybody is slashable.
因此，在Rocketpool中，每个人都可以砍伐。
There may be some kind of seniority of slashing.
可能有某种削减的资历。
So the operator gets slashed first, and then the delegators.
因此，操作员首先被削减，然后是代表人。
But in this model, only the operator can get slashed.
但是在此模型中，只有操作员才能被砍掉。
And people who delegate to this operator,
以及将该操作员委派的人
they can't get slashed.
他们不能被砍掉。
And so now, maybe that's a good model
所以现在，也许这是一个很好的模型
to have as much interested operators as possible working on the network.
拥有尽可能多的运营商在网络上工作。
And I think this proposal, in my opinion, comes with these two premises.
我认为，在我看来，这两个前提都带有这两个前提。
The first one is people want to stick, so I have some if, let's say, and I want to do something with
第一个是人们想坚持，所以我有一些，假设我想和
it, I want to put it somewhere that will give me some kind of return. So there is this idea of
我想把它放在一个会带给我某种回报的地方。所以有这个想法
There's an inevitability that people are trying to maximize and do something productive with their
人们试图最大程度地利用自己
it. So they are going to put it into this liquid staking protocols because you don't want to sit
它。因此，他们将它将其放入该液体放入协议中，因为您不想坐
on the sidelines. And then the second premise is to say, with this it's kind of a magic trick.
在场边。然后，第二个前提是说，这是一种魔术。
So then you can make only the people who are actually staking, so the operators, liable. So
因此，您只能使实际上都有的人使运营商承担责任。所以
So it's, if I get slashed for having delegated
因此，如果我因委派而被砍掉
to someone who does a bad job,
给做不好工作的人
there's no, it doesn't exist anymore.
没有，它不再存在了。
So only the people who have real money on the line
因此，只有在线上有真钱的人
are the ones that are slashable.
是那些可砍的人。
And so that sounds kind of nice,
所以听起来有点不错，
but I think it doesn't necessarily work for it.
但是我认为这不一定对此有用。
I think it's pretty easy actually
我认为实际上很容易
unpack consequences that maybe are different from what we thought of.
解开后果，可能与我们的想法不同。
And so the first issue that I see is that people want it.
因此，我看到的第一个问题是人们想要它。
So when I have Eve and when I'm looking for you, I'm going to try and find ways to get it.
因此，当我有前夕，当我寻找您时，我将尝试找到获取它的方法。
And so if the operator here gets a higher return for putting their money on the line,
因此，如果这里的运营商将钱投入生产线的收益更高，
like they are slashable and the delegators are not,
就像他们是可砍的一样，代表们也不是一样，
we should expect the money of the operator
我们应该期望运营商的钱
to kind of earn them a higher return.
为了获得更高的回报。
And so if I'm a staker,
所以，如果我是斯塔克，
but I don't want to perform the operation,
但是我不想执行操作，
I could go to the operator and say,
我可以去操作员说，
you don't have to put your own money.
您不必自己钱。
I can delegate some of my money to you.
我可以将我的一些钱委托给您。
And so what I think would happen in that scenario
因此，我认为在这种情况下会发生什么
is that the operators would end up
是操作员最终会
getting most of their capital at stake from delegators who give them the money.
从给他们钱的代表们那里，将大部分资本危在旦夕。
So we would recreate, in a way, this operator-delegator separation.
因此，我们将在某种程度上重新创建该操作员划分的分离。
So even if the protocol was trying to enshrine some kind of operator-delegator separation
因此，即使该协议试图赋予某种操作员 - 义师的分离
in that way, the real consequence would be an unbundling which is at that layer.
这样，真正的后果将是在该层的解开捆绑。
So the slashable layer would be unbundled between operators who maybe are putting a
因此，可砍的层将在运算符之间解开，他们可能正在放置一个
bit of money on the line, but most of the stake still coming from people who are chasing
有点钱，但大多数股份仍然来自追逐的人
yield and willing to be placed under these slashable conditions.
屈服，愿意将其置于这些可削弱的条件下。
You could still have people in the non-slashable tier, so these what I call light delegators
您仍然可以在不可斜切的层中有人
that are placing their assets with the heavy operators,
正在与重型运营商一起放置他们的资产
even though it's not slashable.
即使它不可砍。
But then the question is,
但是，问题是，
okay, why should they be getting it, right?
好吧，他们为什么要得到它，对吗？
So these guys on the left,
所以这些家伙在左边，
like the heavy operators and the heavy delegators,
像沉重的经营者和沉重的代表们一样
they are actually providing economic security
他们实际上正在提供经济安全
to the protocol.
到协议。
Like, they're helping the protocol make that claim
就像，他们正在帮助协议提出这一主张
of if something bad happens,
如果发生不好的事情，
a lot of people will lose money,
很多人会亏钱，
including all of these people
包括所有这些人
that are in the heavy stack on the left.
左侧的重堆中。
So what does it mean for the light delegators to get it?
那么，对光代表们获得它意味着什么呢？
Why are we paying them for it?
我们为什么要为此付钱？
What is the useful service that they are providing to the protocol?
他们为协议提供的有用服务是什么？
And so this is a post from Vitalik Buterin, Protocol and Stacking Pool Changes that would
因此，这是Vitalik Buterin的帖子，协议和堆叠池的更改将会
improve decentralization and reduce consensus over head.
改善权力下放并减少头部的共识。
And in this, he mentioned that, okay, there's a few things that these light delegators that
在这方面，他提到，好吧，这些光明的代表们有几件事
are kind of sitting on the side could be doing.
坐在侧面可能会做。
One of them is they could backstop the consensus service
其中之一是他们可以支持共识服务
that the heavy layer is doing.
沉重的层正在做。
So the light delegators, they could run their own prox choice
因此，轻型代表们可以选择自己的代表选择
and they could kind of check whether the people on the left
他们可以检查左边的人是否
here are doing a good job with finalizing the chain
在最终确定链条方面做得很好
and making sure that there's no foul play on that layer.
并确保那一层没有犯规比赛。
So they come in as a second layer of defense,
因此，他们作为第二层的防御，
almost like full nodes, but in between full nodes and the heavy operators, to understand
几乎就像完整的节点一样，但是在完整的节点和重型操作员之间，以了解
whether there is something bad happening on that layer.
该层上是否发生了一些不良情况。
Another thing we could do in the third bullet point is these people on the right, so the
我们在第三个项目符号上可以做的另一件事是这些人在右边，所以
light delegators, once in a while, they could come online and create what's called an inclusion
轻型代表们，偶尔，他们可以上网并创建所谓的包容性
So an inclusionist is a mechanism to bound the execution proposals, including more transactions.
因此，包括包容性的人是约束执行提案的机制，包括更多交易。
So I'll discuss this a little bit more further.
因此，我将进一步讨论这一点。
But the idea here is that the light delegators would be responsible for forcing execution
但是这里的想法是，光代表将负责强制执行
proposals to put transactions into their block.
提议将交易纳入其盖帽。
And this could be a role that the light dedicators are doing here.
这可能是光奉献者在这里发挥的作用。
And so I have this post on it research that I call rainbow stacking.
因此，我在IT上有这篇文章，称为Rainbow堆叠。
And so the idea of how do we organize all of these different services together?
因此，我们如何一起组织所有这些不同的服务的想法？
And I think this is a good way to think about it.
我认为这是考虑它的好方法。
So on the left, we have this service of economic security.
因此，在左边，我们提供了经济安全服务。
the heavy operators that are validating the chain, running this FFG, making this credible commitment,
正在验证链条，运行此FFG的重型运营商，做出了可信的承诺，
so we are not going to do safety faults. And on the right, a stack that is performing these light
因此，我们不会犯安全故障。在右边，正在执行这些光的堆栈
services, so that come in as backstops or as supplements to the consensus services.
服务，因此作为后台或共识服务的补充。
And what I think would happen, or what I think should happen, is contrary to this model where
我认为会发生的事情，或者我认为应该发生的事情与此模型背道而驰
where the light delegators are kind of choosing heavy operators to do services for them or
轻型代表们正在选择重型操作员为他们提供服务或
doing services themselves.
自己做服务。
I think what we would see is again, an unbundling between operators and delegators on the light
我认为我们会看到的是，在光线下，运营商和代表们之间的捆绑
side.
边。
And so the service of sometimes saying, oh, this is what we believe to be the head of
因此，有时说的服务，哦，这就是我们认为是负责人的负责人
the chain, according to our light for choice that we run, or this is the set of transactions
根据我们的选择，链条，或者这是一组交易
that we would really like to see included on chain,
我们真的很想在链上看到
I think the light delegators will let some light operators
我认为轻型代表们会让一些轻型操作员
do that.
这样做。
And so by, how do we do this?
因此，我们该怎么做？
So the light delegators would sort of back
因此，轻型代表们会退缩
the light operators, give them way to say,
轻型操作员，让他们说话，
I believe this light operator is good at providing
我相信这个轻型操作员擅长提供
the service of backstopping the fault choice,
支持故障选择的服务，
or it's good at providing the service
或者擅长提供服务
of making inclusion lists.
列入包含列表。
What's kind of nice in this organization is that because this whole light layer stack
这个组织中的好东西是因为整个灯层堆栈
is not slashable, there's not really a pressure to rebuild this whole liquid stacking protocol
不可砍，没有真正的压力来重建整个液体堆叠协议
with all these trust assumptions and all of this chain of delegations and centralizing
所有这些信任假设以及所有这些代表团和集中
courses.
课程。
So, the light layer, in my opinion, or at least the argument I'm trying to make, should
因此，在我看来，光层或至少我要提出的论点，应该
be more friendly to these solo operators that are potentially
对这些潜在的独奏运营商更加友好
untrusted. So I might not trust this random person on the
不信任。所以我可能不相信这个随机的人
internet to give them my money and potentially they can get
互联网给他们我的钱，他们可能会得到
slashed with it. But if I see them as an active community
用它砍了。但是，如果我认为他们是一个活跃的社区
member on Twitter, doing a good job raising issues on the health
在Twitter上的成员，在健康方面做得很好
of the network, etc, I might say, Okay, you know what, I'll
我可能会说，网络等等，好吧，你知道吗
back you as a light operator for you to perform that
支持您作为轻型操作员供您执行
that useful service to the protocol.
对协议的有用服务。
And so this is the picture that we looked at earlier
因此，这就是我们之前看过的图片
with the problem that the censorship resistance service
审查制度服务的问题
was kind of pegged to the block construction service,
有点与块建筑服务挂钩，
which itself is performed by this
它本身是由此执行的
not very decentralized network of proposals or bidders.
不是非常分散的提案或投标网络。
But we can redraw that pictures and say,
但是我们可以重新绘制那张照片，然后说，
okay, now the heavy layer is going to be responsible
好吧，现在沉重的层将负责
for this consensus service that requires this economic security
对于需要这种经济安全的共识服务
and this credible commitment to good service provision,
以及对良好服务提供的可靠承诺，
the censorship-resistant service will be done by the light layer.
耐心服务将由光层完成。
And that will constrain the block construction service.
这将限制块建筑服务。
And that seems to me like a more proper economic organization
在我看来，这就像一个更适当的经济组织
or more resilient architecture for the provision of this.
或为此提供更多弹性架构。
different services. I have this figure in the post, but I'll just keep it.
不同的服务。我在帖子中有这个数字，但我会保留它。
So just one last thing before I finish. I mentioned this idea of inclusion,
所以在我完成之前只是最后一件事。我提到了包容性的想法，
so the way for people who are not directly involved with the block production to force
因此，对于不直接参与阻止生产的人们的方式
the inclusion of certain transactions. I think to me, the real definition of this
包括某些交易。我认为这是真正的定义
mechanism is yeah a way to make the most out of the decentralization of it so we have all of these
机制是一种充分利用它的权力下放的方法，因此我们拥有所有这些
different stakeholders that are in different places around the around the world with different
不同的利益相关者在世界各地不同的地方
preferences and and having this decentralization force kind of um the block production layer to
偏好并拥有这种权力下放力量的块生产层
not play games to not extract rents uh with the inclusion or not of the user i think it's very
不要玩游戏，以免与用户包含在内的租金，我认为这是非常的
very powerful.
非常强大。
And so you have this EIP-7547 on inclusion list.
因此，您在包含列表上拥有此EIP-7547。
Our team has also opened this open problem
我们的团队也打开了这个开放的问题
looking into different gadgets, so committee-based inclusion
研究不同的小工具，因此基于委员会的包容性
list that increase even more the pressure
列表会增加压力
to include transaction.
包括交易。
And I think the key goal here is this idea of block co-creation.
我认为这里的关键目标是块共同创造的想法。
So you maybe have a very centralized layer
因此，您可能有一个非常集中的层
making the blocks, but you're trying to bring back
制作块，但您正在尝试带回
the force and the pressure of decentralization
权力和权力下放压力
on the makeup of that block.
在该块的构成上。
And so you're really trying to get that transaction input
因此，您确实在尝试获取该交易输入
on chain and get the users on chain
在链条上，让用户进入链条
without games being played.
没有游戏。
All right, yeah, that was a bit of a rough end,
好吧，是的，这有点艰难，
but I hope you enjoyed the presentation
但我希望你喜欢演讲
and do check out our work at the website.
并在网站上查看我们的工作。
Awesome, thank you so much Barnaby.
太棒了，非常感谢您的Barnaby。
Yeah, it was great.
是的，太好了。
It's a lot to digest with the inclusion links,
通过包含链接可以消化很多，
rainbows taking, let's go all the way back to the ETBS.
彩虹，让我们一路回到ETB。
So you have some questions on that.
因此，您对此有一些疑问。
And that is whether there are any existing mechanisms,
这就是是否有现有机制，
any ideas for addressing the bypass ability in ETBS
解决ETB中旁路能力的任何想法
so that developers can still build with some external tool, yeah.
因此，开发人员仍然可以使用一些外部工具来构建。
Right.
正确的。
So there was a mechanism, I mean, there still is, still, I would say, a proposal,
因此，我的意思是，我的意思是，我仍然说，仍然有一个建议
MEV burn, so the idea here was trying to constrain the beacon proposer to,
梅夫·伯恩（Mev Burn
they can't pick whatever builder they want or whatever execution proposer
他们无法选择他们想要的任何建造者或任何执行建议者
want. So the MEdBurn mechanism was using the power of the attesters who are the other parties
想。因此，Medburn机制正在利用其他当事方的证明者的力量
involved in the consensus service to kind of observe the bids that are flying on some gossip
参与共识服务，以观察在某些八卦上飞行的投标
channel and force the beacon proposer to choose a bid that maximizes the value. So that's one way to
通道并强迫信标提案者选择最大化该值的出价。所以这是一种方法
to resolve the credibility problem where the proposer is in control of choosing who the
解决建议者控制谁的信誉问题
builder is.
建筑商是。
I think it's a difficult mechanism and there's been a lot written about it.
我认为这是一个困难的机制，关于它有很多文章。
One of the difficulties is the auction for the bidding rights.
困难之一是招标权的拍卖。
it's kind of happening at the same time
这是同时发生的
as the block value is increasing.
随着块值的增加。
So the auction happens, and while the auction happens,
因此拍卖会发生，当拍卖发生时，
you see more and more transactions trickling
您会看到越来越多的交易流动
into the main pool.
进入主池。
So you're kind of trying to bid on the value
因此，您有点想竞标价值
of like a value that just changes
就像一个变化的价值
while the auction is happening.
拍卖发生的时候。
And this sort of circularity, in my opinion,
在我看来，这种循环
makes the mechanism pretty tricky
使机制非常棘手
to operationalizing in practice.
在实践中进行操作。
So I don't actually think the bypassability
所以我实际上不认为旁路
will be fully resolved.
将完全解决。
Like even if we look at execution ticket,
就像我们看执行票一样，
yeah, we have this credible bid in a sense
是的，从某种意义上说，我们有这种可信的出价
that we have people coming to market
我们有人上市
and telling whether they wanna buy the ticket or not.
并告诉他们是否想购买票。
But once they have a ticket
但是一旦他们有票
and once they become the proposer,
一旦他们成为建议者，
they might still want to outsource the building
他们可能仍然想外包建筑物
to someone else.
给别人。
And so, yeah, I think in many, many different places
所以，是的，我认为在许多不同的地方
that we don't really see the kind of trusted stack
我们并没有真正看到那种值得信赖的堆栈
of MEV Boost disappearing.
梅夫的增长消失了。
I guess it's very difficult to do so.
我想这样做很困难。
Thank you so much.
太感谢了。
That's really great.
那真的很棒。
The next question was to elaborate on the MEV Boost,
下一个问题是详细说明Mev Boost，
which you already kind of did.
您已经做过的。
So yeah, thanks so much for covering that.
是的，非常感谢您的报道。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, yeah, yeah. But then more about the rainbow staking where it's interesting to
是的，是的。但是更多关于彩虹堆积的信息很有趣
be able to have sort of dressless rocket pool kind of staking pool, but what are the other
能够有一种无损的火箭池的藏匿池，但是另一个是什么
implications, for example, on restaking? Because people here compare it to it sounds like enshrining
例如，对重新生产的含义？因为这里的人将其与之相比听起来像是在
I think it's very interesting, Parallels, and definitely I think a lot of these ideas
我认为这很有趣，相似之处，绝对认为很多这些想法
are coming from also observing how risk-taking has developed on Ethereum and sort of like
也来自观察以太坊的冒险性和类似的风险
the ideas of people around it.
周围的人的思想。
So just like briefly, the aspect, risk-taking is like very deep and there's many ways to
因此，就像简短的那样，冒险的方面就像很深，有很多方法可以
think about it, but the aspect that I think is relevant here is the idea of adding more
考虑一下，但是我认为在这里有意义的方面是添加更多的想法
protocol services in this permission this way.
在此许可中协议服务以这种方式。
So, restaking is almost like you're writing services
因此，重新制作几乎就像您正在编写服务
to what the validators are doing,
验证者正在做什么，
but in a way that the Ethereum protocol
但是以太坊协议的方式
that doesn't really see it.
那并没有真正看到它。
So, I don't know as a protocol that you've restaked
所以，我不知道您已将
to promise that you would provision some eigen DA
保证您将提供一些特征
bandwidth for data availability service,
数据可用性服务的带宽，
that this is not something that the protocol is aware of.
这不是协议所意识到的。
What I'm describing here in a way
我以某种方式在这里描述了什么
is the ability to have this interface of,
是拥有此接口的能力，
okay, you have different services
好吧，你有不同的服务
that we could decide to plug in the future.
我们可以决定插入未来。
For instance, we might think, okay,
例如，我们可能会认为，好的，
inclusionless is a good idea to have
包容是一个好主意
as a in-protocol service,
作为协议内的服务，
and that goes into the light stack.
那陷入了轻堆。
Maybe there are services in the heavy stack
也许在重堆中有服务
that make sense, so economic security
这是有道理的，所以经济安全
is mostly useful in my opinion for safety faults, so FFG.
我认为对于安全故障而言，最有用，因此FFG。
But there's been a lot of discussions
但是有很多讨论
around pre-confirmation.
围绕预先确认。
So these need economic security
因此需要经济安全
because you're trying to make this credible commitment
因为您正在尝试做出这一可靠的承诺
of it's a promise that has value that I make,
这是一个有价值的承诺，
I pre-confirm your transaction
我预先确定您的交易
and I promise you that it will be included in this block
我向您保证，它将包含在此块中
or in that rollup.
或在该汇总中。
So there are different things
所以有不同的事情
that require economic security.
这需要经济安全。
are different things that require more widely decentralized set of operators that don't
是需要更广泛分散的操作员集的不同事物
necessarily need to be slashable. So yeah, I think what I'm describing here is a nice interface for
一定需要砍伐。是的，我认为我在这里描述的是一个不错的界面
plugging in these new services to the protocol in a way that mirrors the risk-taking services
以反映冒险服务的方式将这些新服务插入协议
which are out of protocol. I'm still trying to think through the links between the two,
是不合时宜的。我仍在尝试考虑两者之间的链接，
I think it it goes probably a bit deeper than this, but there's definitely something there
我认为它可能比这更深，但是那里肯定有一些东西
in terms of thinking of a protocol as trying to provide all of these services in a way.
在考虑协议方面，试图以某种方式提供所有这些服务。
Thank you. The follow-up on this is whether you could expand a bit more on the heavy services,
谢谢。对此的随访是您是否可以在重型服务方面扩展更多
how to think about them, but also whether pre-confirmations will fall in this heavy state.
如何思考它们，以及预先确认是否会处于这种沉重的状态。
Yeah, so I think the best way to think of a heavy service is to just observe what's currently
是的，所以我认为思考重型服务的最佳方法就是观察目前
on chain today. It's really just people doing the work of signing these votes, attestations,
今天的连锁店。实际上，人们只是在做签署这些选票的工作，证明，
and getting the network to come to finality.
并使网络终结。
What I'm saying in the post,
我在帖子中说的是
or what I'm maybe advocating for,
或我可能提倡的
is we can add these new gadgets to Ethereum.
我们可以将这些新小工具添加到以太坊。
So there are many proof-of-stake protocols out there
因此，那里有许多验证证明协议
in Cosmos, in Tezos, Cardano,
在宇宙中，在Tezos，Cardano，
that have different ways of doing things.
有不同的做事方式。
And some of them have much less, let's say,
他们中的一些人少得多，例如
bare-bones approach to staking.
赤单的锻炼方法。
So one thing that is often reproached to Ethereum is you don't have in-protocol delegation. So that
因此，经常被责备以太坊的一件事是您没有业务委员会代表团。以便
means this is where you have Lido, this is where you have all of these big pools living on top.
意味着这是您拥有Lido的地方，这就是您将所有这些大型游泳池都居住在顶部的地方。
There's many historical reasons. I think it was a semi-conscious choice to go in that direction,
有许多历史原因。我认为朝那个方向迈出的半意识选择，
but that doesn't mean we have to stick to it. So there is this impetus of, okay,
但这并不意味着我们必须坚持下去。所以有这个动力，好的，
Maybe we need the protocol to do more about this,
也许我们需要协议来做更多的事情，
we need to enshrine more things.
我们需要更多的东西。
So again, we've like that same drive to,
再次，我们也喜欢相同的开车，
if we don't see it, we can't control it,
如果我们看不到它，我们无法控制它，
and so let's try to enshrine.
因此，让我们尝试繁殖。
And so what I'm describing here
所以我在这里描述的是
is not what I would call enshrined liquid staking,
不是我所说的液体浸泡，而是
because that, in my opinion, is not possible.
因为我认为这是不可能的。
Like you have to, to enshrine liquid staking
像您必须的那样，以浸入液体
or to enshrine something,
或赋予某些东西，
I'll take Lido as an example,
我以丽多为例
but it's true for all of them.
但这对他们都是如此。
you would have to enshrine the ability for the protocol to curate this set of node operators,
您必须阐明协议能够策划这组节点运算符的能力，
and that introduces, in my opinion, things that may be going too far. But you could still enshrine
在我看来，这可能会走得太远。但是你仍然可以抚养
gadgets that try to lower the barriers to entry for the market of liquid-staking protocols,
试图降低进入液体制定协议市场进入障碍的小工具，
so that make it more competitive, so that you try to prevent dominance of one single protocol that
这样就使它更具竞争力，因此您试图防止一个单一协议的优势
maybe has captured some edge. So leveling the playing field, adding all of these gadgets.
也许捕获了一些优势。因此，将竞争环境升级，添加所有这些小工具。
Okay, you can have native delegation that can be made fungible into a basket of shells.
好的，您可以拥有本地代表团，可以使一篮子壳。
I'm thinking of a liquid stacking module which exists in Cosmos here, and that I also mentioned
我正在考虑这里存在于宇宙中的液体堆叠模块，我也提到
in the post. So there are many ideas I think that we could borrow from other protocols.
在帖子中。因此，我认为我们可以从其他协议中借用许多想法。
which ones are kind of the ones we should settle on
我们应该定居哪些
i don't really know uh i also need to do more research myself
我真的不知道我也需要自己做更多的研究
uh into this but i'm just kind of excited to opening it up and and it's
嗯，但是我很高兴打开它，而且是
something that's been discussed quite a bit both on twitter and
在Twitter和
via this post by vitali mike donkrad harrison um so it does feel like there
通过Vitali Mike Donkrad Harrison的这篇文章
is some kind of rethinking of okay we should be doing
我们应该做的是某种重新思考吗
something about it and and what i'm trying to say here is
关于它以及我想在这里说的是
This is how we should be thinking about it when we are trying to do something about it.
当我们试图为此做些事情时，这就是我们应该考虑的方式。
Thanks very much.
非常感谢。
This is a very interesting topic.
这是一个非常有趣的话题。
There is another question on the differentiation between heavy and light.
关于重和光线之间的差异问题还有另一个问题。
Like from what you're saying, I imagine that the heavy services would be kind of similar
就像您的意思一样，我想重型服务将是类似的
to what the Seekers are doing today, just like running the full stack basically with
对于今天的寻求者所做的事情，就像基本上与
all the responsibilities.
所有责任。
And this would be the higher yield.
这将是较高的产量。
So the question is, what is actually the motivation to run it as the light?
因此，问题是，将其作为光线运行的动机实际上是什么？
To follow the question, why wouldn't the heavy operator continue taking the capital
为了遵循这个问题，为什么重型运营商不会继续夺取首都
and run it all as heavy, slashable capital if it's higher yield?
如果收益率较高，则将其运行为沉重，可削弱的资本？
What is the incentive to run it as light, since we know that disinterested
什么是将其运行的动机，因为我们知道这无私
delegators often don't pay heat to small differences in risk factors?
代表们通常不给危险因素差异很小的差异吗？
And we know that solution givings rarely affect delegators since protocols often cover those
而且我们知道，解决方案很少会影响委派者，因为协议通常涵盖了这些委托人
events.
事件。
Right, yeah, yeah, there's many layers to these questions.
是的，是的，这些问题有很多层次。
Maybe I'll go in the previous direction.
也许我会朝着以前的方向前进。
So if there is some kind of insurance on the risk that you're taking, like if you're staking
因此，如果您要承担的风险有某种保险，例如您正在积累
with someone and that person said, even if I get snatched, nothing bad will happen to
与某人，那个人说，即使我被抢走了，也不会发生任何不好的事情
you, that creates moral hazard, which is this idea of, okay, if I have insurance, I'm going
您，这会造成道德危险，这是这样的想法，好吧，如果我有保险，我要去
to be more prone to maybe having accidents or surveillance.
更容易出现事故或监视。
So it will definitely lower my perception of the risk I'm taking.
因此，这肯定会降低我对我承担的风险的看法。
This is not really something I think that the protocol can really address fundamentally.
我认为该协议确实可以从根本上解决。
not going to let people report to the protocol, oh, this delegate or this operator is offering
不让人们向协议报告，哦，这个代表或该运营商提供的
insurance, it wouldn't be credible, it would be very difficult to control.
保险，这是不可信的，很难控制。
But I do think, yeah, in terms of a distinction between heavy operators and light operators,
但是，我认为是的，就重型操作员和轻型操作员之间的区别而言，
This is also, again, something that I posted pretty recently.
同样，这也是我最近发布的内容。
There's a lot of unknown unknowns and questions
有很多未知的未知数和问题
that I'm not myself fully clear on.
我本人并不完全清楚。
But I think what could happen is very much people
但是我认为可能发生的事情是很多人
who are heavy delegating, they wouldn't
谁是沉重的委派，他们不会
have to choose between heavy delegating and light delegating.
必须在重型委派和委员会之间进行选择。
They could do both in the sense that they
他们可以从某种意义上说
could restate their heavy delegation
可以重申他们的沉重代表团
into the light services.
进入光线服务。
So it would still kind of provide this useful service
因此，它仍然可以提供这项有用的服务
of surfacing who are the light operators
浮出水面的人
that are doing a good job at censorship resistance
在抵抗审查方面做得很好
or at backstopping the heavy operators.
或在重大操作员后退。
So from the heavy delegate perspective,
因此从沉重的代表角度来看，
it wouldn't have to really choose.
它不必真正选择。
I'm not sure if I understood,
我不确定我是否理解，
but I think one part of the question was
但是我认为问题的一部分是
why wouldn't the heavy operators
为什么重型运营商不
become light operators themselves and crowd out these solo stackers that we would want on the
成为轻型操作员，挤出我们想要的这些独奏堆栈者
light operator stage. This is again very speculative and something I'm trying to think through.
轻型操作员阶段。这再次是非常投机性的，我想考虑的事情。
But the idea here would be, yeah, I might trust Lido or Coinbase with my assets when it comes to
但是，在这里的想法是，我可能会相信Lido或Coinbase在我的资产方面
the heavy delegation, because, okay, they run their operations well, it's kind of like money
沉重的代表团，因为好的，他们运行良好，有点像钱
on the line, etc. But when it comes to choosing a light operator, choosing who I back as the
在线等等。但是，当涉及选择一个轻型操作员时，选择我回来的人
provider for all light services, I might use different signals. I might say, again,
提供所有光线服务的提供商，我可能会使用不同的信号。我可能会再说一次
there's this guy on Twitter that always has good takes on how the network is doing, so I'm going to
Twitter上有这个家伙总是对网络的表现有好处，所以我要去
back them with my stake. It's almost like not staking in that regard. It really looks like
用我的股份支持他们。这几乎就像在这方面没有赌注。看起来真的像
it's like token curated membership in a way.
这就像在某种程度上策划的会员资格。
I'm just trying to say,
我只是想说，
this site operator is doing a good job.
该网站运营商做得很好。
So we can't have everyone on the network
所以我们不能让每个人都在网络上
trying to make an inclusion list
试图列出包含清单
and that would be impossible to process.
这是不可能处理的。
So we have still this leader selection problem
所以我们仍然有这个领导者选择问题
of figuring out who are the people
弄清楚谁是人
who should be making the list
谁应该列入清单
or who should be making messages for the protocol
或谁应该为协议发出消息
to read and to execute on.
阅读和执行。
So how do we select these leaders when it comes to the heavy operations?
那么，我们如何选择这些领导者在繁重的行动方面呢？
As a staker with money on the line, I might select conservatively.
作为一名有钱的斯塔克，我可能会保守地选择。
I might say I really require credibility, which means I want to go to liquid-staking protocols that are credible.
我可能会说我确实需要信誉，这意味着我想使用可信的液体制定协议。
So GIDO, for instance, is kind of nice. It has both professional operators, in the future also solo operators.
因此，例如Gido有点不错。将来，它都有两个专业运营商。
That to me it's pretty it shows resilience, so I am willing to put my money to them.
对我来说，这很漂亮，它表现出弹性，所以我愿意把我的钱交给他们。
But then when it comes to the light operators, maybe I have a very different preference function
但是，当涉及到光操作员时，也许我有一个非常不同的偏好功能
based on the fact that yeah, I'm looking for different things now it's not just a money
是的，是的，我现在正在寻找不同的东西，而不仅仅是钱
problem it's in.
问题所在。
Yeah, I'm not sure I there was like many points in that question.
是的，我不确定这个问题是否有很多点。
I hope I answered them.
我希望我回答他们。
Mix it up.
混合。
Nic, let us know if we didn't answer all the questions, but I'm sure you also have a chance to chat with Barnaby elsewhere.
NIC，让我们知道我们是否没有回答所有问题，但是我敢肯定您也有机会在其他地方与Barnaby聊天。
But yes, all answers, thank you Barnaby.
但是，是的，所有答案，谢谢barnaby。
This is all very fascinating. With the delegation and voting, it reminds me, I'm having flashbacks.
这都是非常有趣的。有了代表团和投票，它提醒我，我正在闪回。
Like many years ago, there was a big thing, delegate proof-of-stake, it was some chains
像许多年前一样，有一件大事，代表验证证明，这是一些连锁店
where it implemented it, like 2017 or something like that.
它实施了它，例如2017年或类似的东西。
So what is it maybe difference between those deep post designs and what would become from
那么，这些深度帖子设计和从中变成什么可能是什么区别
the proof-of-stake here?
这里的验证证明？
Yeah.
是的。
Right.
正确的。
Right. I mean it's hard to say because again, I'm not claiming a specific design is better than others.
正确的。我的意思是很难说，因为再次，我并没有声称特定的设计比其他设计更好。
I do think we want to, yeah, there's a strong will to keep this idea.
我确实认为我们想，是的，有一个坚定的想法的意愿。
It's as permissionless as possible to become a validator.
成为验证者尽可能无许可。
So today it is permissionless, like anybody who has 32 it can just come in and stake it and be activated as a validator.
因此，今天它是无许可的，就像任何拥有32个的人一样，它可以进来并将其放置并被激活为验证器。
At the time of, I think, when Proof-of-Stake was starting, I was just joining VEF actually,
我认为，当股份证明开始时，我实际上只是加入VEF，
and there were discussions of, okay, early delegated Proof-of-Stake networks, they exhibit
而且，有关于早期委派证明网络的讨论，它们展示了
very strong power laws, you have most of the stake concentrating to a few big trusted providers.
非常强大的权力法律，您的大部分利益都集中在一些值得信赖的大型提供商上。
Obviously it was very early anyways in Proof-of-Stake, and many things have changed since then.
显然，无论如何，这是很早的验证证明，此后许多事情发生了变化。
So yeah, I feel like there's just like designs that they still look like delegated covers
是的，我觉得就像设计一样，它们看起来仍然像授权的封面
take in the sense of the protocol has native representation of there are people who are
从协议的意义上讲，有一些人的本地代表
operators and there are people who are delegators, but it can be more subtle and more nuanced
运营商，有些人是代表人，但它可能更加微妙，更细微
about the shape of these agreements.
关于这些协议的形状。
So it can say, and it's one thing that really good sticking module does is when I delegate
它可以说，这是一个真正好的模块的一件事是，当我委派时
my stake to someone, I can mint that act of delegation as a share, and I can then provide
我给某人的股份，我可以铸造该代表团作为份额，然后我可以提供
that share to a liquid staking protocol who's going to aggregate all of these shares and
该共享与液体陈设协议共享，该协议将汇总所有这些股份，并且
kind of curate a basket of shares.
策划一篮子股票。
So based on its own, let's say, internal business logic of saying, oh, I'm getting too many
因此，基于它自己的内部业务逻辑，说：哦，我得到了太多
shells of that single operator, so I don't want more, because then I rely too much on
那个单一操作员的外壳，所以我不想要更多，因为那样我太依赖了
them.
他们。
So, there's a lot of heterogeneity in even what people call delegated proof-of-stake.
因此，即使人们称之为授权的有验证证明也有很多异质性。
There's protocols also who have stuff that's called liquid-staking, but I don't think it's
还有一些协议，谁有被称为液体储存的东西，但我认为不是
exactly like liquid-staking protocols as we understand them in Ethereum.
正如我们在以太坊中理解的那样，完全像液体制定协议一样。
So, yeah, I feel like a lot of the effort will be to translate some of these ideas into
所以，是的，我觉得很多努力是将其中一些想法翻译成
proposal that actually makes sense in the Ethereum context. There's been work on this,
在以太坊环境中实际上有意义的建议。有这样的工作，
so Ericsson has a really nice post on that. It's something I'm pretty interested in. I would call
因此，爱立信对此有一个非常不错的帖子。这是我很感兴趣的东西。我会打电话
that the staking user experience, almost. How do I, as a staker, interact with the protocol
几乎是用户体验。作为史塔克，我如何与协议互动
mechanisms and how should these protocol mechanisms be thought about in ways that preserve
机制以及如何以保留方式考虑这些协议机制
values that the Ethereum community kind of looks for in its protocol which is, yeah,
以太坊社区在其协议中寻求的价值观是，是的
as permissionless as possible but also useful. Amazing, thank you, thank you, Barabi, yeah it's
尽可能无许可，但也有用。太棒了，谢谢，谢谢，巴拉比，是的
like I understand it's more vague definition there of like the depots or something like that
就像我知道，在那里更模糊的定义，例如仓库或类似的东西
So yeah, thank you so much for answering that. Sure. We have a comment and question from Nagu,
是的，非常感谢您回答。当然。我们有Nagu的评论和问题，
who, by the way, wrote on our Protocol Studies Wiki whole page about ePBS, and he wants to thank
顺便说一句，谁在我们的协议研究中写了有关EPB的整个页面，他要感谢
you for the article on PBS, where you said PBS is design philosophy, that it's beautiful piece
您在PBS上的文章（您说PBS是设计理念），它是美丽的作品
support. So he asked how long did it take to write it. And a follow-up question is whether
支持。因此，他问写它需要多长时间。后续问题是是否
you have any advice on how to think about these open problems, how to analyze them, where to
您对如何思考这些开放问题，如何分析它们有任何建议
study more, what to study. These are very fascinating problems.
进一步研究，要学习什么。这些是非常有趣的问题。
Yeah, so I guess the first question was how long did it take me to write it? Yeah, if I remember,
是的，所以我想第一个问题是我写了多长时间？是的，如果我记得，
about, not that long actually. So, and this is probably pretty specific to me. And I know
关于，实际上不是那么长。因此，这可能对我来说很具体。我知道
that many people work differently. I tend to be very quiet for a while, just accumulate
许多人的工作方式不同。我倾向于一会儿很安静，只是积聚
input for a long time. And then like the dam bursts and suddenly like I can just write
输入很长时间。然后就像大坝爆发一样，突然我可以写
the whole thing. And I think this piece, I wrote the bulk of it on like a Sunday afternoon
整个事情。我认为这是我像星期天下午一样写的大部分
when things kind of just clicked like the different ways then of course it took it took me
当事物像不同的方式一样点击时，当然需要我
more time to to polish it i what's really nice with this community is the wide network of
更多的时间来修饰它，我对这个社区的真正好处是广泛的网络
collaborators and people being really available so i think i sent it to people in my team people
合作者和人们真正可用的人，所以我认为我将其发送给团队中的人
outside of my team to kind of give comments so that cycle also takes a bit of time but
在我的团队之外发表评论，以便周期也需要一些时间，但是
yeah i feel like when i started being able to articulate the way these different proposals
是的，我觉得当我开始能够表达这些不同的建议的方式时
kind of click together, then it was not very long to write it. And kind of same for the Pepsi post,
有点单击，然后写它不是很长的时间。百事可乐帖子也一样
kind of same for the Rainbow Staking, just at some point it just comes in and then it would take me a
彩虹堆积也一样，在某个时候它才进来，然后我将带我一个
day to just put the whole thing on paper, and then more time to review and really polish it.
一天只需将整个东西放在纸上，然后有更多时间来审查并真正抛光它。
So yeah, so how do you get to that or how do you get more? I think the best way is to read
是的，那么，您如何达到这一点，或者如何获得更多？我认为最好的方法是阅读
as much as possible, like just any paper that has been written or post or blog post or talks.
尽可能多地，就像任何撰写，发布或博客文章或谈话的论文一样。
There's so many talks that are available. What's really nice is like, nice and also sometimes
有太多的演讲可用。真的很好，很好，有时也是
terrifying is the wealth of information on all of these things, it doesn't make sense.
可怕的是所有这些事情的丰富信息，这是没有意义的。
And one advice I often give is to make your own way through it. Don't be afraid to
我经常给出的一个建议是通过它以自己的方式进行。不要害怕
to repeat arguments that people have made,
重复人们提出的争论，
like even write them for yourself,
就像自己写的一样，
but always try to put your own spin on it.
但是，始终尝试将自己的旋转放在上面。
So when I was doing the Epi 1559, I was simulating things.
因此，当我进行Epi 1559时，我正在模拟事情。
So I'm not like a great programmer,
所以我不喜欢一个很棒的程序员，
but I can do basic stuff.
但是我可以做基本的事情。
And so my way of understanding it Epi 1559
因此，我理解它的方式Epi 1559
was let me code like a little toy examples
让我像一个小玩具示例一样代码
and progressively make them richer and richer.
并逐渐使它们越来越丰富。
If you're more like an abstract person,
如果您更像一个抽象的人，
just try to do things.
只是尝试做事。
I'm also very visual,
我也很视觉
so I like to put all these boxes and stuff.
因此，我喜欢放所有这些盒子和东西。
If you're more into data,
如果您更喜欢数据，
find a dataset that's relevant to it
找到与之相关的数据集
and maybe just explore it,
也许只是探索它，
like try to find,
喜欢寻找，
can you prove empirically stuff
你能证明有经验的东西吗
that people are only talking about kind of theoretically?
人们只是在谈论一种理论上？
So yeah, the best way to go about it
是的，最好的方法
is just narrow your focus to the specific thing
只是将您的注意力放在特定的事情上
that you think it's kind of like curious
你认为这有点好奇
So I don't think people have understood it quite well enough,
所以我认为人们对此的了解不够
and I need to bring more of that understanding,
我需要带来更多的理解，
and then just decide on what's the best angle of attack.
然后决定最佳攻击角度。
And that's really personal in terms of what suits you best.
就您最适合您而言，这确实是个人的。
And last thing is don't hesitate to reach out, both myself
最后一件事是毫不犹豫地伸出援手
and anybody I work with I know.
和我认识的任何人。
We obviously have limited bandwidth,
我们显然的带宽有限，
and sometimes my Telegram also is exploding,
有时我的电报也在爆炸，
but generally, I'm always happy to help
但是通常，我总是很乐意为您提供帮助
in as much capacity as I can to review
尽可能多地审查
or to even just get on the phone and shoot through IDs.
甚至只是打电话并通过ID射击。
Amazing, yeah, thank you so much for that Barnaby.
令人惊讶的是，是的，非常感谢您为那个巴纳比（Barnaby）。
And also you are in our Discord server there,
而且您在我们的Discord服务器中，
so I believe people might think you there.
因此，我相信人们可能会认为您在那里。
Thank you, if you have any questions.
谢谢，如果您有任何疑问。
I think this is a great point to wrap up.
我认为这是总结的好点。
We have maybe a few more minutes,
我们可能还有几分钟，
but I think we can finish it here
但是我认为我们可以在这里完成
because we have no more questions.
因为我们没有更多的问题。
And I think we should open it up
我认为我们应该打开它
and then kind of move it over so we can do it in Discord.
然后将其转移到，以便我们可以在不和谐中进行。
Yeah.
是的。
Awesome.
惊人的。
Yeah, thanks so much, Barnaby, again.
是的，非常感谢，Barnaby，再次。
I really appreciate your time.
我真的很感谢您的时间。
I really appreciate you guiding us through all of this,
非常感谢您指导我们完成所有这些，
because it's all very new.
因为这都是非常新的。
It's all quite complex and hard to grasp.
一切都很复杂，很难掌握。
So yeah, thank you so much.
是的，非常感谢。
I really appreciate it.
我真的很感激。
And yeah, we'll see you.
是的，我们会见你。
will see you around the discord and uh the protocol yes sounds good thank you both and
会在不和谐的情况下见到你，嗯，协议是的，听起来不错，谢谢你们俩，
thank you to the people who attended thanks so much barnaby it's always fascinating to
感谢参加会议的人非常感谢Barnaby，这总是令人着迷
to hear you speak.
听到你说话。
Good.
好的。
Bye-bye.
再见。
Awesome.
惊人的。
We'll see you next week.
我们下周见。
So
所以